<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-20T21:44:15+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wanderland Travelers</title><subtitle>Always keep moving, but not too fast</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Our Wonderful Wild Week in Carlsbad, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/20/our-wonderful-wild-week-in-carlsbad-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Wonderful Wild Week in Carlsbad, CA" /><published>2019-02-20T15:45:47+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T15:45:47+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/20/our-wonderful-wild-week-in-carlsbad-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/20/our-wonderful-wild-week-in-carlsbad-ca/">&lt;p&gt;We had such a glorious stay last week in Cardiff by the Sea but with a maximum 7 day stay allowed at San Elijo State Beach it was time to change campgrounds. Luckily we only had to move just a few miles up the coast for a stay at the lovely South Carlsbad State Beach Campground. So similar to San Elijo yet oh so different – it’s just a completely different vibe. The Carlsbad campground was just more quiet, more relaxed, and they had a lot more available campsites. We’re not quite sure why so many more people gravitate towards San Elijo but we’ve got some guesses: it connects to a dog friendly beach, there are several great surfing spots nearby, and it’s a short walk to some nice shopping and groceries. Up in Carlsbad you aren’t nearly as close to the city and the beaches maybe aren’t quite as inviting, but it is equally as beautiful and since it wasn’t fully booked we had several days with an open view of the ocean, even from our ‘back row’ campsite!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Cbad3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smooth rocks on a beach&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;South Carlsbad State Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our stay here was wild in several respects. While our first day was sunny and warm, the next several days had thunderstorms in the forecast. The day I went exploring, storms were expected around 2pm, so I figured I had some time to get video and shots down by the water. The wind had been blowing pretty strong that day so it wasn’t great to be out, but the water was still quite beautiful and I saw some kite surfers down the beach so I headed closer to get some better shots of them, which I did. As I was climbing the stairs back up the campground (now a good 1/2 mile from where I started) I saw lightning strike far off shore and sure enough it started to sprinkle. I quickened my pace as the skies opened up more and ended up in a full run before I got back to the RV. We had some crazy loud thunder and lightning and as things were winding down I saw the sun punching through the clouds and sure enough we had quite the amazing double rainbow right over the RV.  If that wasn’t enough, we also ended up having a beautiful sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Cbad2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pink clouds sunset with cliff and ocean&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A dramatic sky makes every picture better!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister lives in the area and for our next wild experience she took us for an outing to the San Diego Safari Park – what a treat. It turned out to be a cool and overcast day with rain in the forecast which meant that the crowds stayed away! We had such awesome luck with seeing very active animals and I got some really fantastic videos. I’m an animal lover through and through so it was a delight to see them. Most were in spacious enclosures, which counts for so much, and there’s just something so beautiful and almost overwhelming about massive yet peaceful animals. I could’ve watched the elephants for hours and the giraffes are just so majestic. Be sure to check out the full episode below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Cbad4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lion at a zoo&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;This guy was so amazing and making low groaning sounds&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also checked out a unique new ‘sport’ with my sister, axe throwing – which was definitely wild! We appreciated the instruction and helpful hints from the people working there and before long we had pretty much nailed the technique with everyone getting some bullseye hits. They offer 30-minute and 60-minute time slots but 30 minutes was plenty for the three of us. They set you up with two boards and so we all had plenty of opportunity to throw. After that we checked out Twisted Horn Meadery. We got a few different flights and enjoyed everything we tried. I was quite surprised the meads weren’t all that sweet considering they are made from honey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the campground – dogs aren’t allowed on the beach here but there is basically one super long road that runs the length of the campground so most campers enjoy walking and jogging along there. There’s a Ralph’s grocery store within walking or biking distance and it’s not terribly far to get into Carlsbad or head south to Encinitas. Some of our favorite eateries in Carlsbad are Pizza Port (which can be really busy and noisy…so be aware), Harbor Fish Cafe, and Lotus Thai and we also checked out Barrel Republic which is a tap house where you pour your own beer. The amount you consume is monitored by a wristband that you wear and scan each time you pull a tap. They had a ton of options plus several of the locally made gluten-reduced beers – just ask them what’s gluten-reduced when you visit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, another fantastic week on the coast. And a good life metaphor: you can’t have a rainbow without a little rain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/bIcsXH7C4D4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;]" /><summary type="html">We had such a glorious stay last week in Cardiff by the Sea but with a maximum 7 day stay allowed at San Elijo State Beach it was time to change campgrounds. Luckily we only had to move just a few miles up the coast for a stay at the lovely South Carlsbad State Beach Campground. So similar to San Elijo yet oh so different – it’s just a completely different vibe. The Carlsbad campground was just more quiet, more relaxed, and they had a lot more available campsites. We’re not quite sure why so many more people gravitate towards San Elijo but we’ve got some guesses: it connects to a dog friendly beach, there are several great surfing spots nearby, and it’s a short walk to some nice shopping and groceries. Up in Carlsbad you aren’t nearly as close to the city and the beaches maybe aren’t quite as inviting, but it is equally as beautiful and since it wasn’t fully booked we had several days with an open view of the ocean, even from our ‘back row’ campsite!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">San Elijo State Beach: Cardiff by the Sea, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/13/san-elijo-state-beach-cardiff-by-the-sea-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="San Elijo State Beach: Cardiff by the Sea, CA" /><published>2019-02-13T22:16:50+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T22:16:50+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/13/san-elijo-state-beach-cardiff-by-the-sea-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/13/san-elijo-state-beach-cardiff-by-the-sea-ca/">&lt;p&gt;As much as we love to boondock in the middle of nowhere, we still find ourselves drawn to certain destinations and we’re definitely willing to spend a little cash to be there. Whenever possible, our favorite option is to stay in state park campgrounds – there’s usually plenty of natural beauty, you’ll typically find much better rates than private RV parks, they are often close to bike paths, and when you’re along the California coast it’s just one of the best ways to be able to stay beachfront. We lived in North San Diego County for two years before we hit the road and we still love what the area has to offer: that laid back surf town vibe, beautiful beaches, healthy restaurants, great breweries and so much recreation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two people on a trail overlooking the ocean&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Enjoying a sweet little trail in the Self Realization Fellowship gardens&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;san-elijo-state-beach-campground&quot;&gt;SAN ELIJO STATE BEACH CAMPGROUND&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Elijo is a super popular campground among travelers and locals alike, and especially so for surfers. You can make reservations up to six months in advance and you’ll definitely need to plan ahead for a stay here. Reservations are made through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reservecalifornia.com/CaliforniaWebHome/&quot;&gt;Reserve California&lt;/a&gt; website. There are three sections to this campground and our preferred area is the southern section since it puts us closest to the dog friendly section of the beach. We’ve found the middle section to usually be very busy and crowded with little privacy between sites. Most recently we stayed in the northern section and appreciated that it was a little quieter and seemed to have more vegetation between sites. There are many ocean view sites but we always opt for the less expensive back row. You can usually see at least a bit of ocean even from there, or you might get lucky with an empty site in front you, if only for a day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rv with palm trees at sunset&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The northern section has privacy fencing against the highway, which is definitely an added bonus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maximum vehicle length is 35’ and the maximum stay allowed is 7 days. There’s a fee to use the dump station and there are potable water spigots located there as well for filling your tank. Most of the sites are dry camping but there are some hookup sites available for an extra fee. During the summer there’s a camp store and a few laundry machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re sensitive to noise, this might not be the campground for you. The campground backs right up to Highway 101 and next to that are train tracks. The Coaster and Amtrak trains pass frequently during the day, and due to the nearby pedestrian crossing, they really blast their horns. We actually really appreciate the Coaster train – it’s a fantastic option to get around San Diego County, so we don’t mind hearing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cardiff-by-the-sea&quot;&gt;CARDIFF-BY-THE-SEA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big reasons we enjoy staying at San Elijo is that we love the little community of Cardiff! Everything is so walkable, people are friendly, and there’s fantastic dining. We’ve actually needed to get Paco in to the vet both times we’ve stayed here. The Cardiff Animal Hospital is an easy walk from the campground and we’ve appreciated both of the doctors we’ve worked with. The Seaside Market is a delightful, albeit spendy, grocery store with fantastic selections of organic produce, wine, and local beer, as well as the usual grocery store staples. They also have a great deli and seafood counter. There’s Pipes Cafe across the street for breakfast and I make a point to drop by the Rancho Coastal Thrift Store – I always seem to find something I like and it supports the Rancho Coastal Humane Society, which is where we adopted both Paco and Pepper from! We also really love to stop at VG Donuts or grab a pint at Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encinitas&quot;&gt;ENCINITAS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually lived in Encinitas for two years and so we have a close connection to this surfer community as well. It’s a quick bike ride from San Elijo to downtown Encinitas where there are fantastic restaurants, breweries, bars and shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome to Encinitas sign&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We love the Welcome sign --  it definitely captures the spirit of this community!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture Brewing recently opened a tap room here and we were delighted to find that most of the beers they offer are gluten-reduced! As an IPA lover who recently had to give up gluten, it’s been amazing to find several breweries that offer this! Some of our favorite budget friendly eateries downtown are Lotus Cafe, GoodOnYa, Swami’s Cafe and the Potato Shack but if you’re looking for fine dining along here there is plenty. Just a bit beyond downtown is the beautiful and popular Moonlight Beach where you can have campfires or play beach volleyball. If you’ve got the time, you might consider taking in a movie at the historic La Paloma theater or strolling the beautiful and free Self Realization Fellowship gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Busy beach scene with palm trees and volleyball&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The popular and quaint Moonlight Beach near downtown&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also catch the Coaster train here and head off on any number of adventures. We especially love to take it to Old Town (a wonderful place to stroll and get lunch) or all the way to Santa Fe Depot in the heart of downtown, from there it’s just a few blocks to the bayfront and all sorts of dining and sightseeing. We would recommend the inexpensive ferry over to Coronado Island to get amazing views of the downtown skyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;City lights reflecting on the water&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A shot from the ferry, getting ready to dock at Broadway Pier&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really enjoy North County, and all of San Diego, and we’ve made several visits here.
Watch our most recent visit below or check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/WHJIq9kIYa8&quot;&gt;San Diego County&lt;/a&gt; playlist on YouTube. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/jp9uxUdn5FU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;, &quot;Favorite Campsites&quot;]" /><summary type="html">As much as we love to boondock in the middle of nowhere, we still find ourselves drawn to certain destinations and we’re definitely willing to spend a little cash to be there. Whenever possible, our favorite option is to stay in state park campgrounds – there’s usually plenty of natural beauty, you’ll typically find much better rates than private RV parks, they are often close to bike paths, and when you’re along the California coast it’s just one of the best ways to be able to stay beachfront. We lived in North San Diego County for two years before we hit the road and we still love what the area has to offer: that laid back surf town vibe, beautiful beaches, healthy restaurants, great breweries and so much recreation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding Community on the Road</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/06/finding-community-on-the-road/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding Community on the Road" /><published>2019-02-06T09:20:49+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T09:20:49+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/06/finding-community-on-the-road</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/06/finding-community-on-the-road/">&lt;p&gt;Community. It’s something that nearly every person craves and you might think that moving into an RV and hitting the road sounds like a lonely endeavor – well, like many things in life, it will be what you make it to be. There are so many options for meeting other travelers: you might meet people at your campground or your neighbors out in the boondocks or you can go straight to the source and join an RVing group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Several people smiling at camera&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Friendships seem to develop quickly among travelers -- there's so much common ground&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-so-many-options&quot;&gt;THERE ARE SO MANY OPTIONS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some meetups are free but most groups do have a membership fee or you have to buy event tickets, or both. There’s Bob Wells’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cheaprvliving.com/rtr/&quot;&gt;Rubber Tramp Rendevous&lt;/a&gt;: the RTR and the WRTR (which is women-only), these are annual meetups in Quartzsite, AZ. You’ve got the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fmca.com/fmca-events&quot;&gt;FMCA&lt;/a&gt;, the Family Motor Coach Association and the many events they host each year. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rvnomadsthemovie.com/nomadfest/&quot;&gt;Nomadfest&lt;/a&gt; put on by RV Nomads. You might like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rvillagerally.com/&quot;&gt;RVillage Rally&lt;/a&gt; a socializing event with seminars and live music or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://therventrepreneur.com/&quot;&gt;RV Entrepreneur Summit&lt;/a&gt; for networking and strategizing your mobile business. Then there’s the Xscapers – the group we recently joined. The Xscapers are specifically geared towards working age RVers and they host several convergences throughout the year including a trip to Baja, a sky-diving meetup, a summer concert gathering in Colorado and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best part is that you don’t have to chose just one group. We know several folks who attend many of these. Being that we really like to chart our own course, joining just one group made sense for us – we prefer not to have too many scheduled events limiting our travel radius!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Woman hiking in a slot canyon&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There is not one right way to travel or socialize, just get out there and start exploring!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-xscapers-backstory&quot;&gt;OUR XSCAPERS BACKSTORY&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first experience with Xscapers happened totally by accident. It was July 2017 and we were heading to a beautiful boondocking spot in Ketchum, Idaho. I had seen that someone we follow on Instagram was already there. We reached out through the app and made plans to meet. Well, this person knew several other folks in the area as well, and we ended up meeting up with everyone a couple times and learned that most of them were in the Xscapers group. Everyone was really nice and laid back and that kind of laid the foundation for us. The Annual Bash is held every January and since we knew we would be in Florida for January 2018 we didn’t join the group just yet. When we realized we’d be in the desert for January 2019 we figured it was time to see what this group was all about – plus we looked forward to seeing many of those Idaho friends again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV parked in a sweeping green valley&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The sweet spot we stayed at in Ketchum, Idaho&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attending-our-first-bash&quot;&gt;ATTENDING OUR FIRST BASH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually started off this year at the Xscapers New Years Eve party in Quartzsite which was a fantastic way to ring in 2019 and then 12 days later we attended the Annual Bash in Lake Havasu City, Arizona. The Bash was held at the SARA Park Rodeo Grounds and had 300+ RVs and over 500 people in attendance. They offered several different camping areas so you could choose the one best suited to you: the Solar section, Solo Travelers, Families, the Party section, and the General section. We chose Solar, figuring with the abundant sunshine in the desert we’d be just fine. The organizers did say that if there were cloudy days it would be ok to run a generator in that section if it were only for a couple hours, being thoughtful of your neighbors. We ended up having a couple days with nothing but clouds and rain, but Brad was determined not to rev our noisy genny next to our fully solar capable neighbors, and we made it through!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hundreds of RVs parked at the Rodeo Grounds&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;View of the Rodeo Grounds from our hike up Lizard Peak&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Annual Bash was nine days of speakers and presentations, potlucks and happy hours, games and sports, and music and dancing. There were endless opportunities to meet new people and it was easy to bond over all the shared experiences. Brad really enjoyed playing kickball, hiking some of the awesome nearby trails, and the Xscaper Olympics which had three-legged races, pin the sewer hose on the RV, and limbo among many other activities. Some of my favorite events were the 80s Night dance party, yoga, hiking, and the Margarita Throwdown where dozens of people made their favorite recipe and we all sampled them, mingled, and voted for our favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Four new friends in black &amp;amp; white&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our friends Margot and James just before we all had to say farewell&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just had such a positive experience, made so many friends, had many more late nights than we’re used to, and left with unforgettable memories. We truly did find our community on the road. When the Bash ended, many people broke off into smaller groups to caravan to new places. We had a need to go recharge and unwind at the coast and so off we went. While we’ll still mostly be traveling on our own, we very much look forward to those times ahead when we’ll cross paths with our new tribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our video for all the fun:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/E40FoUZEIGQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="RV Community" /><summary type="html">Community. It’s something that nearly every person craves and you might think that moving into an RV and hitting the road sounds like a lonely endeavor – well, like many things in life, it will be what you make it to be. There are so many options for meeting other travelers: you might meet people at your campground or your neighbors out in the boondocks or you can go straight to the source and join an RVing group.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking at Saddle Mountain BLM: Arizona</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/30/boondocking-at-saddle-mountain-blm-arizona/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking at Saddle Mountain BLM: Arizona" /><published>2019-01-30T11:35:13+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T11:35:13+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/30/boondocking-at-saddle-mountain-blm-arizona</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/30/boondocking-at-saddle-mountain-blm-arizona/">&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure when I first saw photos of this camping area on social media but I immediately added it to my list of places we should visit. After a short stay in Tempe, we needed to stick around the area but we were ready to get back out boondocking and it was a great time to check out this spot. Brad discovered that this is one of the highest rated boondocking sites in Arizona on our favorite camp-finding app: Campendium, so we were really looking forward to checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on BLM land with a max 14 day stay and no amenities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS 33.464, -113.0366&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were here Jan.6-9, 2019 and had daytime highs in the 50s &amp;amp; 60s, lows in the upper 30s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a very rough road at the GPS listed above. We would recommend trying the road 2000’ down the highway – we saw many more rigs over there, leading us to believe that area is more accessible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see more photos and reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/saddle-mountain&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Saddle2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yellow daisies with blurry RV in the background&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Wildflowers make any campsite 100x better&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, the road listed at the GPS is pretty dang rough and rocky but we went slowly and were able to make it a few sites in from the road. Some more adventurous souls went in further, a class C was several hundred feet beyond us and a skoolie bus was all the way at the base of the mountain. What we didn’t like about the road was that one side is a lot higher than the other, coupled with rocky terrain, rutted spots, and it was narrow. There just wasn’t a need to push our luck by going in further so we didn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Saddle3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two people eating salads in an RV&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Us being content with our decision&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views were fantastic, it was quiet, and there was hiking to be found however there were SO many dang flies around where we were camped. No matter how hard we tried, they inevitably got in and drove us all bonkers! So awful! It became my daily mission to rid the RV of them, but anytime we opened the door more would find their way in. Some reviewers on Campendium have speculated that campers have been dumping their grey tanks out there which attracted the flies – so we would offer this friendly PSA: it’s illegal to dump your grey tank anywhere other than at a dump station, so just don’t do it! It’s not illegal to collect your water in a bucket, as you are using it, and then pour that outside, but once it enters the grey tank it’s definitley a no go and can get very stinky, very quickly. For more on that, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rvtravel.com/more-on-the-gray-area-of-dumping-the-gray-tank/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; interesting article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Saddle4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Highway with out of focus mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There are inspiring views just about everywhere you look&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as things to do around Saddle Mountain, there are some ATV trails, hiking in the mountains, and probably some good mountain biking. Sunset photography and astrophotography are great out here, and we saw a few folks rockhounding, although I don’t know what they were finding. We were here on work days, so aside from dog walks, we just went for a little drive and when that didn’t pan out (we quickly reached an impassable spot much more suited for ATVs) we got the drone in the air – we always love to get that aerial view when we can!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our video for all the fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/jgMcP-UX-1c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Arizona&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">I’m not sure when I first saw photos of this camping area on social media but I immediately added it to my list of places we should visit. After a short stay in Tempe, we needed to stick around the area but we were ready to get back out boondocking and it was a great time to check out this spot. Brad discovered that this is one of the highest rated boondocking sites in Arizona on our favorite camp-finding app: Campendium, so we were really looking forward to checking it out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking at Hippie Hole: Cibola, AZ</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/23/boondocking-at-hippie-hole-cibola-az/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking at Hippie Hole: Cibola, AZ" /><published>2019-01-23T11:35:13+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-23T11:35:13+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/23/boondocking-at-hippie-hole-cibola-az</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/23/boondocking-at-hippie-hole-cibola-az/">&lt;p&gt;We hadn’t quite figured out where we were going to be for Christmas this year but when Brad mentioned a free boondocking spot on the Colorado River I was quick to sign on. This spot is just a few miles from the Cibola National Wildlife Refuge, on the California/Arizona border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Service land with trash cans, a vault toilet, fire pits and picnic tables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS 33.3771, -114.7057&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were here Dec. 23-29, 2018 and had mild weather with some windy days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We paid $10 to fill our water at nearby Karl’z Country Store&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see more photos and reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/cibola-colorado-river-camping-area&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Hippie2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two people with a big RV in a spacious sandy campsite&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;This definitely makes the list of one of our favorite campsites&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you pull into this camping area, you’ll see 6 pull through spaces, each with a covered picnic table, fire ring, and trash can. There’s a vault toilet at the north end of the gravel lot and the public beach is at that end as well. When we arrived there was only one other camper and instead of the pull through spaces, they had actually chosen a spot right next to the water. We saw a nice big fire ring at another spot right on the water, and the very southern end of the lot, so we thought why not! This gave us a lot of privacy, with thick bushes on either side of us, and there was water access right from the site – although the climb down to it was quite steep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Hippie3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset in a public campground&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There are thick bushes lining the river so not all sites have a river view&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can break away from the peaceful sights and sounds of the river, you should be sure to stop at nearby Cibola National Wildlife Refuge. There’s a 3-mile auto tour in the refuge that allows you to see some really fantastic wildlife – mostly birds but we also saw deer and a coyote. There is a short walking trail within the auto loop that takes you to a blind, where you can get a closer view. I’m guessing we saw SO many birds because we were here during the winter, so keep that in mind during your visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Hippie4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Huge flock of birds flying low&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There were a wide variety of birds to be seen and it was highly enjoyable to see the massive groups in flight&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other noteworthy items from this visit were that on our way to this boondocking site we visited the Blythe Intaglios, which are geoglyphs! They’re artworks created in the ground to be visible from the sky. On the ground you don’t necessarily get a good sense of it but there are placards with images on site letting you know what you’re looking at…and of course we had to put up the drone to really get the bird’s eye view. Pretty amazing stuff. Geoglyphs are difficult to date but these are estimated to be between 450-2,000 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Hippie5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aerial view of geoglyphs: human figure and animals&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;For some scale, look for me in my turquoise shirt&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other bit of excitement was that we caught a mouse in the RV (we use a humane trap baited with peanut butter) and heard another one but it wouldn’t go into the trap. We got a lot of great suggestions for catching mice in the comments section of our YouTube channel so if you’re looking for ideas, go check it out! Oddly enough, we stopped hearing or seeing signs of the second mouse and now, many weeks later, there’s still no further sign of it. I’m guessing it got out and couldn’t find a way back in? Regardless, we’re glad to seemingly be rid of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, we had water access right from our site and the river looked pretty dang inviting. If we had had warmer weather we definitely would’ve launched the kayak and SUP. We saw some brave soul’s swimming at the public beach and their voices carried over the water down to us but we mostly just heard yelps of how cold it was! All in all, this was a peaceful and lovely place to stay, we caught several gorgeous sunsets, and we would definitely return!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Hippie6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brilliant sunset reflecting on a river&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunsets are twice as nice when reflected on water!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s our video from our stay in this beautiful area!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/C9Wk-LQpD-g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Arizona&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;, &quot;Favorite Campsites&quot;]" /><summary type="html">We hadn’t quite figured out where we were going to be for Christmas this year but when Brad mentioned a free boondocking spot on the Colorado River I was quick to sign on. This spot is just a few miles from the Cibola National Wildlife Refuge, on the California/Arizona border.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking at Heart of Mojave East: Needles, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/16/boondocking-at-heart-of-mojave-east-needles-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking at Heart of Mojave East: Needles, CA" /><published>2019-01-16T11:35:13+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-16T11:35:13+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/16/boondocking-at-heart-of-mojave-east-needles-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/16/boondocking-at-heart-of-mojave-east-needles-ca/">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just need a place to stay the night and we’ll always choose BLM land over a rest area or truck stop – those can be so noisy with semis coming and going. Out west BLM land is plentiful and this spot was actually quite scenic, even though we were barely off the highway. One downside to this spot was all the trash around the site. There was a mattress and old tires, lots of broken glass. We collected the smaller items that we could in an effort to leave the site better than we found it – an important way we can help ensure that these lands stay available for us all to enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Mojave3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset behind mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Look for the semi on the road to see how close to the highway we were&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on BLM land with a 14 day stay limit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s listed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/the-heart-of-the-mojave&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt; as a 4x4 location but big rigs would be fine in the large area closer to the road&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS 34.594137, -114.632756&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is no-frills, side of the highway boondocking but there are pretty mountain views and if you have a more rugged vehicle you could go further in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Mojave4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solar panel and distant mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;You can see another rig has driven closer to the mountains &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our intention was to be here only for one night but when we went to roll out the next day, we turned on our Tire Pressure Monitoring System (TPMS) and one of our RV tires was registering a psi of only 45 when we usually keep it around 95psi. We checked it out and could see that we had a nail in the tire and knew it wasn’t really safe to drive on. Thankfully we have roadside assistance through our vehicle insurance, and after a relatively painless phone call to Progressive, we set an appointment to have them come by in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Mojave2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset with layers of mountains in the distance&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;I get excited every time a see a scene like this &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roadside assistance put on our spare tire (which we learned is a 2003 tire and something we should probably replace soon as you shouldn’t drive long distances on it) and off we went to Parker, AZ. We found State Line Tire where they patched our original tire and rotated our tires – all for about $115. They said the patch should last the life of the tire and overall we were really pleased with how well they took care of us! They recommended we tighten all the bolts on the tires after 50 miles of driving but since we didn’t have the right size tools, we rolled back in after we’d put on about 100 miles and they took care of the tightening for free. We can’t say enough great things about that place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our episode and be sure to watch til the end where we visit a super quirky, kind of creepy, roadside attraction!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/jTME-CDH-fw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">Sometimes you just need a place to stay the night and we’ll always choose BLM land over a rest area or truck stop – those can be so noisy with semis coming and going. Out west BLM land is plentiful and this spot was actually quite scenic, even though we were barely off the highway. One downside to this spot was all the trash around the site. There was a mattress and old tires, lots of broken glass. We collected the smaller items that we could in an effort to leave the site better than we found it – an important way we can help ensure that these lands stay available for us all to enjoy!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking at Desert National Wildlife Refuge: Nevada</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/09/boondocking-at-desert-national-wildlife-refuge-nevada/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking at Desert National Wildlife Refuge: Nevada" /><published>2019-01-09T16:22:02+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-09T16:22:02+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/09/boondocking-at-desert-national-wildlife-refuge-nevada</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/09/boondocking-at-desert-national-wildlife-refuge-nevada/">&lt;p&gt;It surprised us to learn that the Desert National Wildlife Refuge – just about 30 minutes north of Las Vegas, Nevada – is the largest wildlife refuge outside of Alaska, at 1.6 million acres! Much of this is inaccessible of course but we enjoyed getting our ‘new’ Nissan Xterra, Frida, out for some 4x4ing to take in the sites. You don’t have to go too far down Mormon Well Rd. to reach the Yucca Forest, which is super impressive, but the road is definitely rocky and you’ll want a high clearance vehicle to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Service land&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are a small handful of sites, all chunky gravel, and there’s a 14 day stay limit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are two fairly large sites near GPS 36.4396, -115.3576 (one on the right and one a little farther on the left)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s an additional site at GPS 36.435307, -115.351500&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a very slow water bottle fountain near the bathrooms at the visitor’s center. We painstakingly filled our 5 gallon jug here&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are fun exhibits in the visitor’s center and a scenic 4x4 drive up Mormon Well Rd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/CC3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV with colorful sunrise and mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;This is a great reminder why it's good to be up before the sun sometimes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed here December 15-16, 2018. The first two sites that you encounter (after turning left just past the visitor’s center) were full so we had to continue another 2 miles down the gravel road. We started thinking we weren’t going to find anything but ended up finding a wide wash that was good enough for a couple nights and there wasn’t any rain in the forecast. We had a ranger come by our site just to make sure we knew there was a 14 day stay limit. He also let us know there was some allowed hunting happening within the refuge (I think he said sheep hunting!). It was just a short stay for us so that we could be close to Las Vegas for some mechanic work but we did still enjoy our time here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/CC1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV in a gravel wash&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It wasn't fancy but it was peaceful and quiet&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Frida (our Nissan Xterra) out on the 4x4 road for her first off-roading adventure was pretty awesome. I logged some more miles driving the stick shift on the way out and Brad drove on the way back. We made it to Peek-A-Boo Canyon and went in a little ways but turned around shortly after, deciding that we’d had enough bouncing on the rocky road! We’re still pretty new to this whole off-roading thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/CC2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nissan Xterra on a gravel 4x4 road&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Frida handled the Mormon Rd. like a champ&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camping area is called Corn Creek Spring and you can find more photos and reviews &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/corn-creek-dispersed&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our episode from this spot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/pIkLY8p8Z9o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Nevada&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">It surprised us to learn that the Desert National Wildlife Refuge – just about 30 minutes north of Las Vegas, Nevada – is the largest wildlife refuge outside of Alaska, at 1.6 million acres! Much of this is inaccessible of course but we enjoyed getting our ‘new’ Nissan Xterra, Frida, out for some 4x4ing to take in the sites. You don’t have to go too far down Mormon Well Rd. to reach the Yucca Forest, which is super impressive, but the road is definitely rocky and you’ll want a high clearance vehicle to do it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Incredible Oregon: Fantastic Stops &amp;amp; Activities</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/04/incredible-oregon-fantastic-stops-activities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incredible Oregon: &lt;br&gt; Fantastic Stops &amp; Activities" /><published>2019-01-04T14:03:25+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-04T14:03:25+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/04/incredible-oregon-fantastic-stops-activities</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/04/incredible-oregon-fantastic-stops-activities/">&lt;p&gt;As you might know, Brad and I live and travel full-time in our motorhome, visiting and photographing as many beautiful places as we can. Oregon is one of those states that is bursting with beauty and we find ourselves passing through every year. Even though we’ve explored a lot within the state, we’re always adding new places to the travel list and are always trying to see new waterfalls – there’s over two hundred! Be aware that the rainy season can be from October through May, but with the right attitude (and outdoor gear) the misty fog, rain showers, and sun bursts just add to the dramatic beauty  of the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’ve compiled isn’t meant to be an exhaustive list of Oregon tourist destinations (I don’t even have Portland on the list – that deserves it’s own post!) rather it’s a collection of some of our favorite stops and things to do. You can find videos about most of these places on our Oregon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL8m4FF4S9RxY-9gshqPVIRE6S41Zx9Vgb&quot;&gt;playlist&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado: some of our absolute favorite things to see and do in the gorgeous green state of Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/OregonSites.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Numbered point on a map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-crater-lake-national-park&quot;&gt;1. CRATER LAKE NATIONAL PARK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Klamath County&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 42.920289, -122.162369&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue sky and incredible blue water at Crater Lake&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The unbelievably blue water of Crater Lake&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are a number of National Monuments and National Historic Sites in the state of Oregon, Crater Lake is its only National Park. People from all over the world visit this fairly remote alpine lake to gaze at its incredible deep blue and crystal clear waters. Crater Lake is the deepest lake in the US and it’s also considered one of the snowiest inhabited places in the US as well – snow is typically on the ground from October through June and often into July, meaning that the rim drive around the lake has a very short window of being fully open. Swimming is allowed in the lake, but only at one place, accessed from the Cheetwood Cove Trail. There are several unique rock formations and spires in the park worth checking out and the star-gazing can be downright incredible. Wildfires have become more common in the area in the Fall, with hazy skies obscuring views of the lake. Camping is available in the park or hotel rooms are available at Crater Lake Lodge – although you might have to book this up to two years in advance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We tent camped in a campground within the park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-samuel-h-boardman-scenic-corridor&quot;&gt;2. SAMUEL H. BOARDMAN SCENIC CORRIDOR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brookings, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 42.191800, -124.367000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dramatic beach with many off-shore sea stacks&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Secret Beach at low tide&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The southern Oregon coast is arguably the most beautiful section of coastline in the entire state – full of off-shore sea stacks, arches and natural bridges. The Samuel H. Boardman Scenic Corridor stretches 12 miles along Highway 101, with several small pull-outs and short trails leading to jaw-dropping beauty. Arch Rock, Natural Bridges, Secret Beach, and Seal Cove (GPS above) are all fantastic stops and easily searchable on Google maps. Secret Beach is only accessible at low tide, so be sure to check tide tables as you plan your visit. It does require some agility to scramble down the rocks to Secret Beach and always be aware of dangerous sneaker waves – a common occurance on the Oregon coast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Harris Beach State Park in Brookings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-face-rock-state-scenic-viewpoint&quot;&gt;3. FACE ROCK STATE SCENIC VIEWPOINT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bandon, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 43.105089, -124.433922&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ocean scene with large rocks offshore&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Being here at low tide was absolutely incredible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing Face Rock had been on my list for many years but I didn’t realize what an incredible spot it actually is. I had thought that the only draw was the large off-shore rock resembling a face, but there are in fact dozens of rocky spires out in the water and close to shore that make this one enchanting place. What made our experience unforgettable was visiting here during a negative tide (an extreme low tide) and serendipitously at a time when artist Denny Dyke had created one of his incredible sand drawings. He does them four times a month and you can check out his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sandypathbandon.com/public-schedule&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to see the schedule.
While the view from the parking lot is great (seen above) we would definitely recommend taking the stairway down to the beach. At low tide you’ll find sea caves and tide pools, and you’ll be able to get really close to some of the towering rock formations. Be aware, the parking area is a small loop and can only accomodate about 15 cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Bullards Beach State Park in Bandon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-seal-rock-state-recreation-site&quot;&gt;4. SEAL ROCK STATE RECREATION SITE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seal Rock, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.497365, -124.082790&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset on the Oregon coast with rocky spires&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We caught this beautiful sunset on my birthday a few years ago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You really can’t go wrong visiting anywhere on the Oregon coast so if you find yourself along the central portion we highly recommend visiting Seal Rock State Recreation Site – and all the better if you can visit at low tide and/or sunset. Not only is there the massive Elephant Rock (not pictured), jagged spires rise out of the water not far off shore and with binoculars or a zoom lens you might just spy some seals hanging out on the distant rocks. Tide pools reveal anenomes, starfish and other wonders. Nearby is the charming town of Yachats, a perfect place to incorporate into this visit. Check out the local fare at Yachats Brewing or get oyster shooters and seafood lasanga at nearby Drift Inn. The Green Salmon is a popular little bakery and a great spot to grab breakfast or coffee. The coastline along this small town is especially rocky and picturesque, and several available beach rental homes make this an excellent place to spend a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; McKinley’s Marina &amp;amp; RV Park in Waldport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-float-the-willamette-river&quot;&gt;5. FLOAT THE WILLAMETTE RIVER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eugene, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.045233, -123.026374&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;woman on a kayak with people on a beach&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Spending time at the river is a great way to beat the summer heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better summertime activity is there than being on the water on a hot day. While much of the river between Springfield and Eugene is a calm easy float, there are definitely sections that require your attention and one in particular that requires some swift maneuvering. We always launch from the boat ramp at Island Park (GPS listed above), then, after a little more than a river mile you’ll encounter a section that requires you to make a hard right to go around a fairly swift curve. There will be a sign saying to stay to the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of Willamette River with guiding arrows&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;You'll need to follow the path of the white arrows, just before passing under Interstate 5 (a large concrete bridge)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a real possibility that your watercraft could flip so always wear a life jacket, carry a whistle, and let someone know your plans that day. That being said, floating the Willamette is one of our favorite summertime activities and is mostly quite relaxing. There are a couple different sections of small rapids that add a little excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eugene is also home to many fantastic restaurants, breweries, coffee shops and bakeries so be sure to include some dining in your day out. For food we would recommend Cornucopia, The Bier Stein, Sushi Pure, Cafe Yumm, Pizza Research Institute, Metropol Bakery, and Tacovore. For breweries we love Oakshire, Coldfire, Hop Valley and Ninkasi. For great views of downtown, take a drive up Skinner Butte or for a good workout consider hiking up Spencer Butte or Mount Pisgah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Not helpful…we’ve just stayed with friends when visiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-visit-sahalie--koosah-falls&quot;&gt;6. VISIT SAHALIE &amp;amp; KOOSAH FALLS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sisters, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.348302, -121.995797&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking at a raging waterfall from the top&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Be sure to check out the trail that takes you to the top of Sahalie Falls -- definitely worth it for a closer look&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An incredible amount of beauty lies between Eugene and Bend along Highway 126 so pack a picnic and take a day to explore it! Sahalie Falls is an impressive 100’ tall waterfall flowing over a moss-covered natural lava dam. The viewpoint for Sahalie is just a short walk from the parking area (GPS above). On sunny days this powerful waterfall casts a rainbow in it’s mist, adding to the magic. There’s a side trail to the right that will take you to the top of Sahalie Falls. Be sure to also take the time to hike downstream along the clear turqouise waters of the McKenzie River to reach Koosah Falls, another impressive waterfall dropping 70’ into a wide pool – about 30 minutes on a pine covered trail, with some steps, through the lush forest. You can make it a 2.6 mile loop by continuing to Carmen Reservoir crossing to the other side of the river, and walking back upstream to Sahalie. If parking at Sahalie is full, there’s also a lot at Koosah Falls. While you’re in the area, you might consider the hike to Tamolich Pool (aka Blue Pool), taking a soak at Belknap Hot Springs Lodge, or paddling on nearby Clear Lake with it’s incredible clarity – you can see preserved trees on the lake bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve only visited here en route to Bend or as a day trip from Eugene –not as an overnight stop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-explore-the-city-of-bend&quot;&gt;7. EXPLORE THE CITY OF BEND&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bend, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.031876, -121.566307&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large and fast moving waterfall&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It's a relatively short and easy walk from the parking lot to get this view of Tumalo Falls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the outdoor enthusiast or craft beer lover, Bend is a place not to miss. This hip mountain town on the Deschutes River has more breweries per capita than any other city in Oregon. Download the Bend Ale Trail app to check-in at the breweries you visit – some offer check-in perks like Buy 1, Get 1 deals. While you can’t really go wrong in choosing a brewery, we especially enjoy the food and beer flights at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craftoregon.com/&quot;&gt;Craft Kitchen &amp;amp; Brewery&lt;/a&gt;.  Visit Mt. Bachelor for winter or spring skiing or in the summer for hiking and mountain biking.  The Les Schwab Ampitheater draws quality music acts every summer so be sure to check out their events calendar. If you love to be on the water,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oldmilldistrict.com/stay-play-bend/how-to-float-deschutes-river/&quot;&gt;floating&lt;/a&gt; the Deschutes River is fantastic way to spend an afternoon – there are even outfitters to help you with gear rental and shuttling. Tumalo Falls (GPS above) is an easy but popular hike about 10 miles west of town. There’s a $5 parking fee or it’s free with your National Parks pass. With it’s fairly small parking lot, visiting on a weekday is recommended. Get great photos just a short walk from the lot then head to the top of Tumalo Falls for dramatic views. You can continue hiking upriver another mile to reach Double Falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We boondocked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/forest-road-260&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in the National Forest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-hike-at-smith-rock-state-park&quot;&gt;8. HIKE AT SMITH ROCK STATE PARK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terrebonne, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.363860, -121.140409&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rocky cliff walls and spires with a river&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It can get really hot in the summer months so make sure to hike with plenty of water&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unique stop in central Oregon is just 45 minutes north of the city of Bend, but feels like a little slice of Zion National Park. We loved the challenging 5-mile Misery Ridge loop. You can see the switchbacks of this trail in the above photo. If you prefer a more mellow visit strolling along the river still offers beautiful views, although it is a fairly steep trail down to the river. Smith Rock State Park is also a super popular rock climbing destination with more than 1,000 bolted climbing routes. The park itself can get incredibly busy, so we would suggest trying to visit on a weekday. With parking for about 400 cars, the park easily sees 3x that many visitors on warm weather weekends. There are 6 RV parking spaces located at the GPS coordinates above but no RV camping anywhere at the park. There’s a day use fee of $5 with self-pay stations near the parking areas. To see more about the park amenities, tent camping, and hiking trails check out the state park &lt;a href=&quot;https://oregonstateparks.org/index.cfm?do=parkPage.dsp_parkPage&amp;amp;parkId=36&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve stayed overnight at the Walmart in Redmond (1 night only) and we’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/forest-road-260&quot;&gt;boondocked&lt;/a&gt; outside Bend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-paddle-trillium-lake-at-mt-hood&quot;&gt;9. PADDLE TRILLIUM LAKE AT MT. HOOD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mt. Hood National Forest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 45.266408, -121.741273&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandy lakeshore beach with snow-capped peak in the distance&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Now how inviting is this scene!?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mt. Hood is one of Oregon’s most recognizable peaks and it’s highest. Just about an hour and a half drive from the Portland airport and Hood is known for having almost yearround skiing. Timberline Lodge offers offers daily skiing until September and October, then it switches to weekends, as conditions allow. There are many beautiful alpine lakes in the area but we love the accessiblity and view from Trillium Lake. Bring a picnic and blanket and enjoy the views from shore or if you want a more unique experience, rent a canoe, kayak or paddleboard from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mthoodoutfitters.com/&quot;&gt;Mt. Hood Outfitters&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a $5 day use fee at this lake. We like to park in the lot closest to the beach pictured (GPS above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Trillium Lake Campground&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-hike-the-multnomah-wahkeena-waterfall-trail&quot;&gt;10. HIKE THE MULTNOMAH-WAHKEENA WATERFALL TRAIL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Columbia River Gorge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 45.575253, -122.128178&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two impressive waterfalls&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Multnomah Falls on the left and the difficult-to-access base of Ecola Falls on the right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hike is a fantastic way to experience the majesty of the Columbia River Gorge, just 25 miles east of the Portland airport. Multnomah Falls is definitely one of the most iconic waterfalls in the state and worth seeing just on it’s own but if you’re looking to experience even more of Oregon’s gorgeous waterfalls, there are nearly 50 along this scenic highway corridor! Regarding the Multnomah-Wahkeena hike: not only do you experience Multnomah Falls from the top and bottom, you’ll see five other beautiful falls, and several unnamed falls. This is a moderate 5-mile roundtrip loop. You can hike the loop in either direction but we started at the Wahkeena Falls trailhead (GPS listed above) and ended at Multnomah. There is significant elevation gain along the hike but also flatter portions. This area can be extremely busy and parking can be difficult, so arriving early in the day is definitely recommended. There are lots of other waterfalls nearby and most of them are labeled on Google maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We boodocked in Cascade Locks but unfortunately it’s no longer allowed at that spot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-explore-the-city-of-astoria&quot;&gt;11. EXPLORE THE CITY OF ASTORIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Astoria, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 46.181140, -123.817029&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge and marina on a sunny day&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Astoria-Megler Bridge as seen from the marina&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many quaint little communities along the Oregon Coast but possibly none so famous as Astoria. It’s the oldest city west of the Rockies, it’s where Lewis and Clark ended their westward expedition (well, technically at Fort Clatsop just 5 miles southwest of Astoria), and it’s been the backdrop of several movies including The Goonies, Short Circuit, Into the Wild, and The Ring. Astoria sits in the very northwest corner of Oregon where the Columbia River meets the Pacific Ocean. Not only are there fantastic breweries– Buoy and Fort George are favorites – there’s also the riverwalk (fun to explore by foot, bicycle or trolley) and climbing up the Astoria Column to get great views of the area (GPS above). We would recommend visiting the wonderful Sunday Farmer’s Market or heading to Fort Stevens State Park to see the ghostly remains of the Peter Iredale shipwreck, which ran aground in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Golf Course &amp;amp; RV Park in Astoria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-explore-the-wallowa-mountains&quot;&gt;12. EXPLORE THE WALLOWA MOUNTAINS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joseph, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 45.280887, -117.211842&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crystal clear lake surrounding by mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Clockwise from top left: Wallowa Lake, Views from Mt. Howard, and views along the Hurricane Creek Trail&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wallowa Mountains are an unexpected and awe-inspiring gem located in the far northeast corner of the state. They’re known as the Swiss Alps of Oregon and it’s no surprise that this area also makes it on the Seven Wonders of Oregon list. It’s definitely an out of the way place to visit, but oh so worth it. This area sees a lot of winter snow, so the best time to catch open trails is during the summer months. RV sites are available at Wallowa Lake State Park (GPS above) and at a handful of nearby RV parks – be aware that reservations can fill quickly. In addition to boating and kayaking on the gorgeous lake be sure to hit some of the hiking trails. We loved the Hurricane Creek trail in the Eagle Cap Wilderness. For especially dramatic views take the tram up Mt. Howard and hike the 2 mile loop at the top. Tram tickets are a bit spendy at $35/person but the ride is adventurous, the views are phenomenal and at the top there’s a cafe with outdoor seating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Wallowa Lake State Park and nearby Scenic Meadows RV Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, your turn! We’d love to hear about your favorite stops in the state. Leave us a comment below with your must-see places in this Pacific Wonderland.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Oregon&quot;, &quot;Favorite Campsites&quot;]" /><summary type="html">As you might know, Brad and I live and travel full-time in our motorhome, visiting and photographing as many beautiful places as we can. Oregon is one of those states that is bursting with beauty and we find ourselves passing through every year. Even though we’ve explored a lot within the state, we’re always adding new places to the travel list and are always trying to see new waterfalls – there’s over two hundred! Be aware that the rainy season can be from October through May, but with the right attitude (and outdoor gear) the misty fog, rain showers, and sun bursts just add to the dramatic beauty of the landscape.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wrapping Up in St. George: Utah</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/02/wrapping-up-in-st-george-utah/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wrapping Up in St. George: Utah" /><published>2019-01-02T16:22:02+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-02T16:22:02+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/02/wrapping-up-in-st-george-utah</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/02/wrapping-up-in-st-george-utah/">&lt;p&gt;As you might know from our previous St. George post, Brad had gotten our new car all set up to be towed behind the motorhome…except that when we went to hook up and leave, none of the lights were working on the car. This meant another week in town so he could troubleshoot the problem but it also meant we got to spend a little more time with family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Geo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Three people on a sandy hiking trail&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Brad with his sister and brother-in-law on the trails&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we had all ready moved the motorhome with the intention of rolling out, it was a good time to freshen the tanks and get more propane. We struck out at our two usual places for doing that and ended up finding Nielsen RV. They have a free dump station and fresh water spigots, and propane for sale, all right in their parking lot making for a very convenient stop. We picked up some toilet paper from their store as well, but cringed later when we looked at the receipt and saw we had paid nearly $8 for a 4-pack – highway robbery! I also spotted a women’s hybrid bike for sale on craigslist that had barely been ridden, so we went and picked that up too. I’m actually pretty sad to say goodbye to my old beloved clunky cruiser, Oscar, but it was just so heavy and only had three gears – this new one can fly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all our weeks in St. George, we’d certainly enjoyed the outdoors by mountain biking, playing pickleball, and rock climbing but there were also many days spent working and being knee deep in projects, so when we finally got a break in the cooler weather, we were more than ready for a hike. We connected with Brad’s sister, her family, and his mom to head over to Snow Canyon State Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the trails here are fairly short but offer breath-taking scenery. We did the Hidden Pinyons trail, a short and relatively easy 1.5 mile loop. Then we headed over to check out the Petrified Sand Dunes. There’s a short walk from the parking lot and then are some trail markers after you hit the dunes, but we just enjoyed meandering on them and catching the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Geo3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People hiking as the sun sets&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;You should definitely include a stop at the Petrified Sand Dunes at Snow Canyon State Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were walking along the dunes, we also noticed this super interesting phenomenon – crazy, right!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/Geo4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sand balls forming on top of sandstone&quot; /&gt;
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/Geo5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;little balls of sandstone&quot; /&gt;
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as figuring out our tow car wiring situation, Brad dove right in. His dad had done a lot to assist with the first round of wiring and they had even tested out the lights by directing power from the battery to different pins on the trailer cable socket, with success – so it was a bit perplexing at first when things didn’t work. His dad was no longer in town but they had some helpful phone conversations. Since the pins on the socket had worked, Brad figured it was likely an issue further upstream, so he tested different connections with the multimeter, which led him strengthen all the wire connections within the cable. He did the same for the connection plug on the RV. He removed the 5-to-4 wire converter and upgraded to a six diode lighting system in the car. He also discovered the tail lights on the motorhome and the car weren’t receiving power because of a blown fuse which was easy enough to replace. It made us realize we had no idea how long that fuse had been blown and how long we’d been driving around without tail lights. We’ve resolved to check on those much more often! It was a huge relief to get that all figured out and I’m continually amazed by Brad’s willingness and skillfulness in tackling mechanical and electrical projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/Geo6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two people smiling&quot; /&gt;
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other fun little bits from our last week in St. George were that we checked out some holiday lights at the Red Hills Desert Garden and we put a big Wanderland Travelers decal on the side of the RV! There goes our anonymity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See all the fun in our video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/6gRvTCcatSw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Utah&quot;, &quot;Our Nissan Xterra&quot;]" /><summary type="html">As you might know from our previous St. George post, Brad had gotten our new car all set up to be towed behind the motorhome…except that when we went to hook up and leave, none of the lights were working on the car. This meant another week in town so he could troubleshoot the problem but it also meant we got to spend a little more time with family.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rock Climbing at Prophesy Wall: St. George, Utah</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/12/25/rock-climbing-at-prophesy-wall-st-george-utah/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rock Climbing at Prophesy Wall: St. George, Utah" /><published>2018-12-25T17:41:46+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-25T17:41:46+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/12/25/rock-climbing-at-prophesy-wall-st-george-utah</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/12/25/rock-climbing-at-prophesy-wall-st-george-utah/">&lt;p&gt;Our time in St. George was full of many firsts for me: learning to drive a manual, going mountain biking, and playing pickleball, but I’d have to say rock climbing was definitely the most epic ‘first’. Brad’s sister Julie and brother-in-law Riley are outdoor lovers, and avid mountain bikers and climbers. We’d been dropping hints that we’d love to go climbing with them sometime and during this visit to St. George we finally got our chance. While Brad had been climbing before it was over a decade ago so we were stoked to have such experienced people taking us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Climb2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Four people standing in front of Prophesy climbing wall&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Lots of joy to be outside and to be taking on a challenge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St. George is known internationally as a climbing destination and it actually has more climbing routes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.summitpost.org/st-george-rock-climbing/352917&quot;&gt;per capita&lt;/a&gt; than any other US city.  Not only are there several different types of stone in the area to climb – limestone, sandstone, and granite – with St. George’s mild winters you can climb yearround (but be aware that summers temperatures often hit 100°F). Riley chose Prophesy Wall as our crag for the day. Our first route was Ship of Fools: an 80’ climb with a 5.8 difficulty rating. Riley was up first lead climbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Climb3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man rock climbing placing caribiners and rope&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Riley placed the caribiners and rope as he went up&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brad was up next and his job was to unclip the rope from the caribiners as he went, but of course leaving the rope in place at the top. Brad said his forearms were probably the most tired muscle after he was done. Even though it’s best to try and keep the brunt of the weight on your legs, it’s so easy to get stuck in spot where you’re relying on your arms more as you look for your next move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Climb4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man rock climbing taking a large step and reaching&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;I think Brad's height is a big advantage in the search for a good hold&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie was third and she collected the caribiners. She had done a fair amount of climbing before meeting Riley and their first date was actually to go climbing at Prophesy Wall! It was a joy to climb with those two and they were so helpful and patient with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Climb5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Woman climbing golden sandstone&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Julie on our second route: Whatever Happens...Happens&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the last to go and thankfully didn’t have to think about anything other than finding my way up the wall. It’s funny, I found that when I had a really good handhold and solid footing, there’s this desire to stay and enjoy the comfort of the spot, especially when you’re next move is unclear. Riley’s great advice: look for the chalk marks to find your next hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Climb6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Woman climbing sandstone wall&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Climbing was definitely a great mental and physical challenge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ship of Fools was a really great route with big handholds and footing. I think it was the perfect introduction to climbing. We followed the same order and duties for our second climb: Whatever happens…Happens. This one had a difficulty rating of 5.9 and was a bit more challening. It was 100’ of climbing and once I got to the crux (the most difficult section of the climb) I just couldn’t find a good route. My muscles were getting really tired and I actually called it quits and repelled back down. Everyone else made it to the top of that one. Then Julie and Riley took turn climbing both routes again to clean up any remaining gear. Some clouds had rolled in before we started the second route and the temperature was continuing to drop as we neared sundown, so I think we were all pretty ready to get back to the warm car once we had everything all packed up. All in all it was a really great experience and we look forward to doing it again – maybe we’ll even get our own gear someday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our video of climbing at Prophesy Wall:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/S5x7k_XjzP8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="Utah" /><summary type="html">Our time in St. George was full of many firsts for me: learning to drive a manual, going mountain biking, and playing pickleball, but I’d have to say rock climbing was definitely the most epic ‘first’. Brad’s sister Julie and brother-in-law Riley are outdoor lovers, and avid mountain bikers and climbers. We’d been dropping hints that we’d love to go climbing with them sometime and during this visit to St. George we finally got our chance. While Brad had been climbing before it was over a decade ago so we were stoked to have such experienced people taking us!</summary></entry></feed>