<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-28T22:42:04+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wanderland Travelers</title><subtitle>Always keep moving, but not too fast</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Beach Camping in New Mexico</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/new%20mexico/2018/11/10/beach-camping-in-new-mexico/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beach Camping in New Mexico" /><published>2018-11-10T18:10:47+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T18:10:47+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/new%20mexico/2018/11/10/beach-camping-in-new-mexico</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/new%20mexico/2018/11/10/beach-camping-in-new-mexico/">&lt;p&gt;People often ask us how we find these gems, these beautiful places. Well! We keep an adventure list, organized by state, and we’re always updating it as we learn of great spots. We get tips from fellow travelers, travel magazines, or sometimes we just see a green space on the map and read up on it. Pro tip: we also check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campendium.com&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt; and sort by the highest-rated free campsites in an area. Anyway, when we were leaving Albuquerque we realized we could incorporate a stay at the beautiful Elephant Butte Lake State Park and so our plan was set. If you look up photos of this place, you’ll see a popular destination with cars dotting the shoreline and boats filling the lake. Well, those must be from the height of summer because that’s about the opposite of what we found coming here in mid-October!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elephant Butte Lake State Park is in SW New Mexico, just two hours south of Albuquerque on Interstate 25&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The park has 4 campgrounds with hookups that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://newmexicostateparks.reserveamerica.com/camping/elephant-butte-lake/r/campgroundDetails.do?contractCode=NM&amp;amp;parkId=430010&quot;&gt;reservable online&lt;/a&gt;, and they also offer first come, first serve primitive beach camping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are many areas of soft and deep sand, so be careful driving on the beach and try to stick to the main thoroughfares&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water spigots are available throughout the paved areas of the park and there is a dump station available at the Desert Cove campground&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be sure to fit in a visit to one of the many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sierracountynewmexico.info/attractions/truth-or-consequences-hot-springs/&quot;&gt;hot springs spas&lt;/a&gt; in nearby Truth or Consequences, NM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-week-at-the-lake&quot;&gt;OUR WEEK AT THE LAKE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the thing that really got us interested in this state park was not just the dramatic views and meandering coastline but, you guessed it, the fact that they allow camping right on the beach. When we stayed here the rate was just $8/night with a 14 day stay limit. After 14 days, you need to vacate for at least one week before returning. With over 200 miles of shoreline, there are nearly endless opportunities for where you can primitive camp, however, be aware that there are many areas of deep sand and getting stuck is a real possibility. It’s always a good idea to scout the area ahead of time to make sure the sand is hard packed. We had no problems on the main roads, it’s the off-shoots that you need to especially be careful on. We saw several people staying on the shore over by the marina but we headed the opposite way. We had no problems on the main roads, it’s the off-shoots that you need to especially be careful on. To get to our spot you would head right shortly after the paved road turns into gravel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/EB1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV camping next to a lake&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It was a little rugged coming down into our spot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather wasn’t really ideal during our stay – we arrived in the sunshine but then had three solid days of wind, rain, and clouds. So much so that we weren’t generating enough solar power and relied on our generator a number of times to keep our laptops powered and the batteries happy. Highs were in the low 50s for most of our stay and evenings were chilly enough that we ran our propane heater every night. We spent much of our time after work cozied up, watching movies and drinking wine – we found a really enjoyable Hatch Chile Wine (red and green varieties) which had just a bit of heat and was a fun way to enjoy some of the local flavor. I made several hearty meals to keep our bellies warm – Pumpkin Curry soup, Black Bean Chili, and Mushroom Gravy on Veggie Hash. We had hoped we might get a chance to paddle on the lake but it wasn’t in the cards for this trip. When the sun finally came out, the lake looked truly magnificent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/EBLake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lake with mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Oh, that glorious sunshine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lake attracts a huge number of birds and we loved seeing and listening to them all. There were American white pelicans on their annual migration and we saw blue and white herons, ravens, swallows, terns, and grebes. The blue herons seemed to be the dominant bird and they would even scare off the white heron from the favorite fishing spots. In fact we had quite the close encounter with a heron at our campsite. We have no idea what he was up to but he hung out for a good long while!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/EBbradHeron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man next to large heron&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Love it when the locals come to say hello&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, our days here were super relaxing. Brad of course worked his normal 8-5p work week and I did my usual video days on Monday and Tuesday. On Wednesday I ran a bunch of errands in Truth or Consequences:  I did four loads of laundry at Soap-n-Suds laundromat, I swung by Martha’s gift shop to get some of the famed and delicious New Mexico Piñon coffee, I stopped for some groceries at Walmart. On those sunny days I enjoyed wandering around with camera but I was so disappointed to see so much garbage on the beach. I grabbed some gloves and a bag and cleaned up what I could around our site, but there was so much more. I was especially upset about all the fishing line left behind to get tangled around all the birds. I will never understand how someone can spend time out in nature and then spoil it by leaving their garbage strewn about, having such a huge impact not only on the wildlife but also on all the future visitors to that place. We’re all in this together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/EBSunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pink clouds and lake&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It's a beautiful world&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway! We did really enjoy this area and really look forward to coming back a little earlier in the season to enjoy some warmer weather and definitely to get out and paddle on the lake. Side note – after we left, we passed through the town of Hatch which was completely decked out with chiles everywhere you looked. They’re the Hatch Chile Capitol of the World! There were huge bundles of chile peppers hanging from about every storefront roof and the buildings were painted so bright and colorful. It looked like it had so much character and I bet you can find some delicious food there. I definitely want to stop next time we’re in the area!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out our video all about our stay at Elephant Butte Lake State Park:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/IDWzZRcxdTU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="New Mexico" /><summary type="html">People often ask us how we find these gems, these beautiful places. Well! We keep an adventure list, organized by state, and we’re always updating it as we learn of great spots. We get tips from fellow travelers, travel magazines, or sometimes we just see a green space on the map and read up on it. Pro tip: we also check out Campendium and sort by the highest-rated free campsites in an area. Anyway, when we were leaving Albuquerque we realized we could incorporate a stay at the beautiful Elephant Butte Lake State Park and so our plan was set. If you look up photos of this place, you’ll see a popular destination with cars dotting the shoreline and boats filling the lake. Well, those must be from the height of summer because that’s about the opposite of what we found coming here in mid-October!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Albuquerque and the Balloon Fiesta</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/11/08/albuquerque-and-the-balloon-fiesta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Albuquerque and the Balloon Fiesta" /><published>2018-11-08T18:10:47+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-08T18:10:47+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/11/08/albuquerque-and-the-balloon-fiesta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/11/08/albuquerque-and-the-balloon-fiesta/">&lt;p&gt;When we left Colorado, our original idea was to spend a week in Taos but with a chilly forcast showing overnight temps there dropping into the low 30s, we decided we should keep moving south. I found that Albuquerque was a good twenty degrees warmer all around and so we made that the destination. It wasn’t until Brad started looking into camping options that we realized the International Balloon Fiesta was currently going on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Albuquerque hosts the International Balloon Fiesta the first full week of October every year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is on-site &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.balloonfiesta.com/guest-guide/rv-information&quot;&gt;RV camping&lt;/a&gt; available but you’ll definitely want to book ahead – we were able to find camping at Enchanted Trails RV park the day before we arrived but this was over 25 minutes from the Fiesta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are morning and evening sessions at the Fiesta and each day offers a different schedule so check the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://balloonfiesta.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to learn more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be sure to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; for more tips to make your visit a great one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our stay in Albuquerque was brief but we enjoyed visiting Old Town and Red Door Brewing &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddoorbrewing.com/&quot;&gt;Red Door Brewing&lt;/a&gt; which offered several gluten-removed beers!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-nights-in-albuquerque&quot;&gt;TWO NIGHTS IN ALBUQUERQUE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at our campground, Enchanted Trails RV Park, we pulled into our site and realized that the small trees on either side of us were positioned directly in front of both of our slides. No matter how repositioned, we were going to damage either the RV or the trees if we put the slides out so I went back to the office to see if they had any other sites. The woman working in the office was incredibly kind, which was very much appreciated, and she switched us with a much smaller rig who hadn’t arrived yet and who wouldn’t have any trouble fitting into our site. Funny enough, the new site still had us right against a tree on one side but we were able to pull far enough forward that it wasn’t a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was going to be a short stay, we finished getting set up, walked the dogs, and then headed out the door to get a little taste of the town. First up was a visit to Old Town Albuquerque.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/ABQus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;people and Albuquerque sign&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Welcome to Old Town&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Night was falling fast so we just walked around a bit, enjoying the architecture and the colorful store fronts.  A man on the street corner played an amplified pan flute and it was just a lovely evening to be outside. Many stores had hot air balloon decorations and we popped into one that carried an assortment of local coffee, crafts, and clothing.  After a little while we hopped back in the car and continued to nearby Red Door Brewing – their downtown location. I had read that they offer gluten-removed beers and was delighted to find that the majority of the beers on their menu were such. I thoroughly enjoyed the IPA and Brad said the milk stout was fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/ABQbeer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;two people in a brewery&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Brad loves my enthusiasm for this gluten-removed IPA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kept it a pretty early night, made it home for dinner and set our alarms for 4:45am. We actually attempted to buy our Fiesta tickets online that evening but the website kept malfunctioning once we were at the shopping cart. We would need to buy them tomorrow. After a sleep that seemed just a few hours, with coffee in our thermos and all our camera gear packed, we left the RV at 5:35am. We headed to the Cottonwood Mall where we would need to buy tickets on-site and from there take the shuttle to the Fiesta. The parking lot was a buzz of people and busses and excitement. We waited in the ticket line for about 10 minutes before boarding the bus and at that point it was starting to seem like a stretch to get to the Fiesta in time for the Morning Glow at 6:30am. The website had said it was a 20 minute shuttle ride but once we got within a few miles of the Fiesta the traffic was at a crawl. We could see a bit of the Glow happening from the bus windows but it was clear we were going to miss it. That was definitely pretty disappointing – it was a big reason for getting up so early! Lesson learned, if you’re unable to camp on-site, definitely allow a lot of extra time for traffic, especially on the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived, the Mass Acension had begun but as we learned, this process is fairly lengthy – I mean there are over 500 hot air balloons that launch! We were able to walk right into the thick of everything, getting so close to all the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/ABQ1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hot air balloons&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A sea of people and balloons&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our favorite ways to capture the action was to set up a camera on a tripod and take timelapse video. We brought a GoPro, our trusty Lumix, my Nikon, and we had our phones so since we had tons of ways to take photos and video, it was easy to dedicate one to doing timelapses. But that footage was so fun to watch later: the hot air balloons raising from the ground up in seconds, twirling as they lifted off, and it just helped you to see the scale and scope of the event. Another pro tip: we brought a giant thermos of coffee and snacks, and wore all kinds of layers so we were able to keep comfortable and didn’t have to spend any extra money while we were there. However, on the way home we passed a Natural Grocers so we popped in to get some veggies for a late breakfast hash and Brad went over to a nearby donut shop, Rebel Donuts, where they actually had some gluten free ones. We were home shortly after 10am and were super happy to get back to our little nest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/ABQnap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;man and dog napping together&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Pep and her papa catching a little more shut eye&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out our video, if for no other reason than to see the awesome balloon timelapses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/CJCCcClMa5M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><summary type="html">When we left Colorado, our original idea was to spend a week in Taos but with a chilly forcast showing overnight temps there dropping into the low 30s, we decided we should keep moving south. I found that Albuquerque was a good twenty degrees warmer all around and so we made that the destination. It wasn’t until Brad started looking into camping options that we realized the International Balloon Fiesta was currently going on!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Great Sand Dunes National Park</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/colorado/national%20parks/2018/10/26/great-sand-dunes-national-park/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Great Sand Dunes National Park" /><published>2018-10-26T10:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T10:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/colorado/national%20parks/2018/10/26/great-sand-dunes-national-park</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/colorado/national%20parks/2018/10/26/great-sand-dunes-national-park/">&lt;p&gt;After our time in Manitou Springs, we made the three hour drive south to check out Great Sand Dunes National Park. We had heard how impressive the giant dunes are and were excited to see it with our own eyes. Our last National Parks pass expired a couple months ago, so at the entrance station we purchased our third annual pass since living on the road. It’s still a STEAL at $80 for the whole year. Not only does it get you into every national park and monument, it has also covered our parking fee at different national forest hiking and recreation sites. Worth every penny, or as my dear friend Jessica would say: it’s cheap at twice the price!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We camped at nearby San Luis Lakes State Wildlife Area – a free stay after you purchase your Colorado State Parks pass or the Colorado Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife pass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The campsites have 30/50amp service and there was a dump station and vault toilets but no running water. The National Park, however, has a dedicated fresh water spigot at their dump station&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can hike on the dunes! Pro tip: bring or rent sleds and snowboards to glide down the dunes…or at least try to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/grsa/planyourvisit/hiking.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more hiking options in the National Park, including climbing Mount Herard and visiting the Sand Creek Lakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out nearby &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colorado.com/articles/hidden-colorado-gem-zapata-falls&quot;&gt;Zapata Falls&lt;/a&gt; – note that a high-clearance, 4x4 vehicle is recommended for making the rocky 3.5-mile drive to the trailhead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking for nearby hot springs? We loved &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sanddunespool.com/&quot;&gt;Sand Dunes Recreation&lt;/a&gt;, especially their adults-only area with four hot pools, a sauna, and alcoholic beverages for purchase all inside a lush greenhouse full of plants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-windy-dramatic-beautiful-place&quot;&gt;A WINDY, DRAMATIC, BEAUTIFUL PLACE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Brad found us a ‘free’ campground about 15 minutes from the park at the San Luis Lake State Wildlife Area. In reality, you actually need to buy a pass to stay here. We didn’t really know what kind of pass we needed, so at Walmart when they told him it was $70 for the Colorado State Parks pass, that’s what we got. When we arrived at the campground, the signs stated that the pass was $36, and we later learned that you can get away with having the Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife pass which is $36, but doesn’t get you into the state parks. We figure we’ll be back in Colorado within the year and will be sure to take advantage of having that state park pass. This camping area is exceptionally beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GSDcamp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV and mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Every site has an incredible view&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s large! There are so many sites, all with electric hookups (30 and 50 amp).  They have vault toilets, a basketball hoop, and a central dump station but no running water anywhere in the campground. We had put some water in our tank before leaving our campground in Manitou Springs but we also ended up getting 6.5 gallons inside the National Park. There is a dedicated fresh water spigot available at the dump station there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather was pretty crazy during our stay. When we arrived the nearby mountain range, the Sangre de Cristos, were bare but after the first night they had a light dusting of snow on their peaks and looked all the more incredible. It was cloudy and moody and WINDY. Like, crazy fairly-uncomfortable-to-be-outside windy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GSDstorm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mountain storms&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It looked like this every night we were there&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first day in the area we went into the National Park, but because Brad’s foot is still healing from an ankle sprain that happened in Iowa, we didn’t want to push it and just walked to the base of the dunes…which honestly was probably still a bit much for him. We were still completely in awe of these giant, magnificent sand dunes. They are the tallest in North America and even being right next to them, it’s hard to comprehend the scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GSD2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sand dunes&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We loved the patterns in the sand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GSDMlittle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;person and sand dunes&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Can you see me out in the field?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day at camp I snagged several timelapses of the ever-changing clouds and mountain views and we both worked all day. Our internet speeds were pretty slow so I wanted to finish my Wanderland Travelers video on Monday to have plenty of time to upload it over the unpredictable AT&amp;amp;T network. We started the upload Monday night and lo and behold it was ready to go Tuesday morning! I’m not used to having Tuesday “off” so I went into the park on my own. I made the long walk to the base of the dunes and even climbed up a couple but the wind was so out-of-control strong and freezing (and pelting me with tiny grains of sand) that an hour out there was plenty. I had worn long johns, pants, tall socks, hiking boots, a t-shirt, flannel, long cardigan, coat, scarf and hat and was still cold out there! The scarf and sunglasses were particularly key in helping shield my face from the stinging grains of sand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening I took a walk with my camera over to the lakefront next to the campground and caught a little bit of a rainbow. I also got to see my first jackrabbits of the season. Well, I saw their butts as they hopped away and of course the telltale black tips of their ears. We love them so much! Unfortunately the land of jackrabbits also happens to be the land of goathead thorns and I even saw a few cholla cacti at Great Sand Dunes…we’re always sad for the dogs to be back around thorny things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GSDRainbow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rainbow and mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Quick snap of the rainbow before it disappeared&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in reading reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campendium.com&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt; for the San Luis Lakes campground I learned that there were nearby hot springs. Google didn’t let me down and I learned of two places but the one that stood out FAR above the other was called Sand Dunes Recreation (not a terribly inspired name, but I digress). It was only about 20 minutes from our campground but we packed up and moved to stay right there on the property. This place has a 100 degree swimming pool with two diving boards, a baby pool, and a large therapy hot tub that could easily fit 20 people or more. They have an onsite restaurant serving breakfast, lunch and dinner and an RV park with hookup sites and dry camping (10 spaces of each). They also rent out toys, towels, and even swimsuits, but best of all is the adult-only area called “the Greenhouse”. Literally built inside an old greenhouse and full of plants everywhere, they have a dry sauna, a long skinny hot pool, three piping hot smaller pools (including the Coffin at 110 degrees!) and they serve beer and wine – a pretty large selection at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GSDGreenhouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hot tub in a greenhouse&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Coffin hot tub&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This place is seriously incredible. Not only is it beautiful with so many soaking options, it’s quiet enough that we had many of those all to ourselves…of course they’re so dang hot you don’t spend much time in any one of them…but it was truly blissful. Oh, and since we stayed in the RV park (dry camping for $20/night) we got half-off admission, regularly $12 each. Plus on Wednesdays it’s only $2 each to enter the Greenhouse (regularly $5/each). Score score score! It was such an unforgettable experience and definitely the best place we’ve ever just ‘happened’ upon. Be sure to include an overnight there when you visit Great Sand Dunes National Park but be aware that it is closed every Thursday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s our video from our visit to this gorgeous area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/lnuHUnkZFRg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Colorado&quot;, &quot;National Parks&quot;]" /><category term="Scenic Camping" /><category term="Hot Springs" /><summary type="html">After our time in Manitou Springs, we made the three hour drive south to check out Great Sand Dunes National Park. We had heard how impressive the giant dunes are and were excited to see it with our own eyes. Our last National Parks pass expired a couple months ago, so at the entrance station we purchased our third annual pass since living on the road. It’s still a STEAL at $80 for the whole year. Not only does it get you into every national park and monument, it has also covered our parking fee at different national forest hiking and recreation sites. Worth every penny, or as my dear friend Jessica would say: it’s cheap at twice the price!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Colorado Springs and Garden of the Gods</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/colorado/2018/10/20/colorado-springs-and-garden-of-the-gods/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Colorado Springs and Garden of the Gods" /><published>2018-10-20T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/colorado/2018/10/20/colorado-springs-and-garden-of-the-gods</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/colorado/2018/10/20/colorado-springs-and-garden-of-the-gods/">&lt;p&gt;It’s always so fun to figure out what path and direction we’re going to take when we have a far-off destination in mind. We pull out our road atlas (yes, a paper map!) and start looking at all the options, and it’s very exciting to envision ourselves on different adventures along these different routes. When it came time to leave Iowa, we knew we would be heading towards the Southwest for the winter but we didn’t know what we wanted to see on the way there. It didn’t take long to realize that we might be able to catch some of the golden Aspens in Colorado helped us make our decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are tons of camping options in the area but we stayed at Pike’s Peak RV Park – a Good Sam park – which put us just 10 minutes from Garden of the Gods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 15 miles of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gardenofgods.com/your-visit/visit1/trails-and-hiking&quot;&gt;trails&lt;/a&gt; within Garden of the Gods. We enjoyed the 1.5 mile paved Central Garden loop which takes you closest to some of the iconic rock formations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visiting during the Fall? We loved seeing the golden Aspens on our drive to Cripple Creek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you gluten-free? We discovered that Colorado has tons of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coloradobrewerylist.com/brewery_otherdrinks_type/gluten-freegluten-reduced-beer/&quot;&gt;breweries&lt;/a&gt; offering gluten-free and gluten-removed beers!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t forget to drive to the top of Pike’s Peak and keep reading for more hiking and exploring ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;westward-ho&quot;&gt;WESTWARD HO!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed at Pike’s Peak RV Park, which is just a 10 minute drive to Garden of the Gods. This is in the eastern half of Colorado, very close to Colorado Springs, but the actual city we stayed in was Manitou Springs. It’s a small RV park and you are incredibly close to your neighbors but you have some mountain views, there’s a babbling stream in the park, and there’s a liquor store and a cute little coffee shop just a block away. We also appreciated the reasonably priced laundry machines at $2 wash/$2 dry. This is a Good Sam park, so be sure to get your discount when you call for a reservation. Funny sidenote, the power pedestal at our site ended up not working but we were able to plug into the one behind us and share it with our neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/PPPark1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV in campground&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our site at Pike's Peak RV Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first night in town we visited Garden of the Gods. Man did it feel great to be back in mountain country! It was busy near sunset but we still were able to find time to ourselves on the paths. We decided to walk the Central Garden loop because it brought you really close to some of the most magnificent rock formations. There were so many birds, singing beautiful little songs to each other and there were SO many magpies in the park. In one field I bet there was over 30 of them. We made it back to the car after about an  hour or so and the sun had just fallen behind the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GoDUS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People and mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Us on the Central Garden Loop&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GoDB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Person and mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;These rock formations reminded us so much of Moab, Utah&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/GoDSunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rocks and susnet&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We caught a little sunset color before we left the park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fieldhousebrew.com/beer-list/&quot;&gt;FH Beerworks&lt;/a&gt; – chosen because they offer a few different house brewed gluten-free beers! Normally they have three on tap but when we visited they were out of the stout. The Milletology gluten-free IPA was fantastic. This area of town was pretty busy so we were a bit worried about parking but the brewery had a small lot in back and there were a handful of open spaces there. There was also a food truck in the back serving the brewery guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our Aspen/fall colors drive, we were debating between going to the top of Pike’s Peak or taking a scenic drive to Cripple Creek. Each takes about an hour to get to the destination. We were definitely leaning towards the Peak but when I checked the webcams on the mountain, it showed that the view was entirely socked in by clouds. It was sunny up there, but looking down all you saw were clouds. It would have been a cool experience but it wasn’t really what we were hoping for up there, so we decided to do the drive to Cripple Creek. There are several pull-outs along the highway to stop and soak up the gorgeous views and golden leaves and we passed what looked to be a very popular hiking trail &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/colorado/horsethief-falls-trail&quot;&gt;Horsethief Falls&lt;/a&gt;. There are also several roads off Highway 67 that you can explore down – just be sure to respect that some are private drives. The town of Cripple Creek itself is adorable and has a rich history as a gold mining town. The area has been revitalized and is full of cute shops, coffee houses and more casinos than I could count (a huge reason for the town’s revival!). We also read that there is a pack of wild roaming donkeys that sometimes stroll down main street but we didn’t see them on our visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/COAspensUS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People dogs and yellow aspens&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We pulled off the highway to get a closer view of the trees&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/COCrippleCreek.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People and mural in mining town&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Cripple Creek was so cute&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our stay in the area was quite brief and there were a lot of things we still have on our adventure list for next time. We would have loved to hike in the Red Rock Canyon Open Spaces, explore &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.broadmoor.com/broadmoor-adventures/seven-falls/&quot;&gt;Seven Falls&lt;/a&gt;, hike the famed Manitou Incline, check out the Red Mountain hiking trail, drive up Pike’s Peak, visit the unique &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bishopcastle.org/&quot;&gt;Bishop Castle&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miramontcastle.org/&quot;&gt;Miramont Castle&lt;/a&gt;, and just get to stroll more in the charming area of Manitou Springs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about this area and our time here, be sure to check out our vlog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/-ieM0AsnyVs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="Colorado" /><category term="Cities" /><category term="Autumn" /><category term="Hiking" /><summary type="html">It’s always so fun to figure out what path and direction we’re going to take when we have a far-off destination in mind. We pull out our road atlas (yes, a paper map!) and start looking at all the options, and it’s very exciting to envision ourselves on different adventures along these different routes. When it came time to leave Iowa, we knew we would be heading towards the Southwest for the winter but we didn’t know what we wanted to see on the way there. It didn’t take long to realize that we might be able to catch some of the golden Aspens in Colorado helped us make our decision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to our blog!</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/10/18/welcome-to-our-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to our blog!" /><published>2018-10-18T10:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-18T10:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/10/18/welcome-to-our-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2018/10/18/welcome-to-our-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Hi there and welcome to our little blog. We figured it was about time that we added this facet into our digital presence, I mean, we’ve only been full-time RVing for two and a half years now! When we first started this traveling lifestyle, I was so engrossed in capturing it in photos and film – it’s what felt most intuitive to me and to be honest I’ve been a bit intimidated about the written part. But in the spirit of trying new things, especially things that push you outside your comfort zone, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/BBigBend2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man on Mountain&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Brad living on the edge in Big Bend National Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/MaggieStGeo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Woman and red rock cliffs&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Me deciding if I should literally take the leap&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love that with this written component people will be able to do keyword searches and easily find the info they’re looking for, as opposed to our main content arena: YouTube. You can gleam a fair bit from our video descriptions but you’d kind of have to watch through a whole video to catch all the little tips we throw out there. But be sure to still check the videos out too! Making videos of our travels is definitely a passion of mine and we seriously end up capturing some pretty spectacular footage: starlapses, moonrises, wildlife, and those funny little moments that just don’t translate into writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/DesertStars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Long exposure photo of star movement&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Winter nights in the Anza Borrego Desert&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I really wasn’t sure where in our timeline to start the blog. I mean, there are so many past adventures worthy of posting about, but I think what I’ll do is just start with the present. There will definitely be throwback posts to some of our favorite places, and we’ll do some compilation posts:  Best Hikes in Arches, Top 5 Free Campsites and so on. I’m sure we’ll include posts about our must have RVing gear and our camera equipment, all that good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what else can you expect from this blog?
Details! Where we camped, the cost, hiking trails, and helpful hints like where we provisioned or found propane. We love to boondock (free dispersed camping on public lands) as much as possible, so we’ll also share the hidden gems we find along the way. You’ll probably read about us picking up trash at a BLM campsite, whether we felt safe in a remote spot, where we dropped off our recycling, and whether or not a small-town grocery store carried organic produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/CactusFendy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rv and Cactus&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Boondocking in the Sonoran Desert&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since one of my passions is nature photography, you can also expect to see lots photos of this incredible world of ours. Brad’s also going to contribute posts about RV repairs and maintainence or about any number of his repurposing projects (think: homemade sandals made from tire treads!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog will really be a complement to our YouTube channel – which we’ve had going from the start. We post new videos every Wednesday and the channel has an enormous amount of travel inspiration, so  be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/wanderlandtravelers&quot;&gt;check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect that this blog will evolve over time and hopefully my voice and writing skills with it! I also hope this will become a place to meet other travelers, share information, and create community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/FamCO.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People and dogs at Colorado welcome center&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our little traveling family&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time~&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="Ramblings" /><category term="Misc" /><category term="OurStory" /><summary type="html">Hi there and welcome to our little blog. We figured it was about time that we added this facet into our digital presence, I mean, we’ve only been full-time RVing for two and a half years now! When we first started this traveling lifestyle, I was so engrossed in capturing it in photos and film – it’s what felt most intuitive to me and to be honest I’ve been a bit intimidated about the written part. But in the spirit of trying new things, especially things that push you outside your comfort zone, here we are.</summary></entry></feed>