<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-26T16:43:28+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wanderland Travelers</title><subtitle>Always keep moving, but not too fast</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Two Days in Death Valley: Badwater, Zabriskie &amp;amp; Much More</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/28/two-days-in-death-valley-badwater-zabriskie-much-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Days in Death Valley: Badwater, Zabriskie &amp; Much More" /><published>2019-03-28T16:16:25+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-28T16:16:25+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/28/two-days-in-death-valley-badwater-zabriskie-much-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/28/two-days-in-death-valley-badwater-zabriskie-much-more/">&lt;p&gt;What comes to mind when you think of Death Valley National Park: scorching heat? An endless expanse of dry brown earth? Depending on when you visit, it can definitely be insanely hot, but endless brown it is not! When we visited in late February we were stunned by the colorful badlands, diverse landscapes, and the beautiful weather! It’s truly a photographer’s paradise and we want to share with you some of absolute best places to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travel by RV and found a great free camping area called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/the-pads&quot;&gt;The Pads&lt;/a&gt;, just about 20 minutes from the first stop on our list! This free campsite is just a little outside the east boundry of the park – hence our reason for sticking to this side for our explorations. There are no amenities here (no electricity, drinking water, dump station, etc) and there is no cell connectivity. Not too far away though is the Furnace Creek Visitor’s Center where you can pick up a little slow cell service and there’s an outdoor water spigot for filling portable jugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zabriskie-point&quot;&gt;ZABRISKIE POINT&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Death5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sunset over striped badlands&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Anytime of day here will be beautiful but we certainly enjoyed it at sunset&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a short but steep paved walkway to the overlook here, offering truly magnificent views of the colorful badlands below. This is a fantastic spot for sunrise or sunset. Brave souls might consider exploring a few of the different narrow dirt trails around the area for alternative, and less crowded, views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;badwater-basin&quot;&gt;BADWATER BASIN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Death2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Super white salt flats&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The hexagonal shapes in the salt are just so cool!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the absolute must-see places within Death Valley. It does require about a mile walk before you get to the sand flats, over some pretty bumpy terrain – we saw people struggling a bit with strollers. Once here you can appreciate the intricate patterns that have formed in the extremely salty lake bed, what was once Lake Manly. This is another spot that’s beautiful anytime but if you get any color in the sky for sunset, it will look amazing coupled with the endless expanse of the salt flats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;devils-golf-course&quot;&gt;DEVIL’S GOLF COURSE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Death3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man walking on crazy salt formations&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;I don't think pictures can really do this place justice -- just go!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was quite the unexpected gem within the park – from the initial photos I saw, it wasn’t a priority to stop here but it would be a mistake to miss, especially since it’s on the way to Badwater Basin. These are also salt formations but they’re entirely different from what you see at Badwater. The terrain here is incredibly sharp and probably not suitable for kids to walk on but you can appreciate it right from the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;artists-palette-drive&quot;&gt;ARTISTS PALETTE DRIVE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we missed this on our trip, but if you have the time you should definitely check out the colorful striations in the rocks on this one-way loop drive. Just be aware that vehicles over 25’ long are not allowed on this road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;golden-canyon-hike&quot;&gt;GOLDEN CANYON HIKE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Death6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;woman hiking up a steep incline&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Slowly making my way towards Manly Beacon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do this hike a couple of ways:  as a loop starting and ending at the Golden Canyon trailhead via Gower Gulch (4 miles RT) or as a loop starting and ending at Zabriskie Point (6 miles RT) – we did this second option. There are quite a few awe-inspiring views and I will say the stretch up towards Manly Beacon is very steep and strenuous. Also be sure to pay good attention to the trail route signs. All in all, it’s a magnificent way to explore the badlands of the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;20-mule-team-canyon-drive&quot;&gt;20 MULE TEAM CANYON DRIVE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Death4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;road and colorful badlands&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;This was techically taken from the highway but shows the type of badlands that you'll be taken through&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another one-way loop drive that takes you through some incredible scenery. There are a few areas to pull over and little trails you can explore. This one isn’t quite as exciting as some of the other options on this list, but if you have the time, it’s a nice addition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope we’ve given you some great inspiration and planning ideas for your trip to Death Valley National Park! There are of course so many things to see and do, including the Mesquite Flat Sand Dunes, The Racetrack, Darwin Falls and more but if you’re pressed for time, these are a great introduction to a gorgeous park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out our video exploring this magical place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/yv8RdDkjmNQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;National Parks&quot;, &quot;California&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">What comes to mind when you think of Death Valley National Park: scorching heat? An endless expanse of dry brown earth? Depending on when you visit, it can definitely be insanely hot, but endless brown it is not! When we visited in late February we were stunned by the colorful badlands, diverse landscapes, and the beautiful weather! It’s truly a photographer’s paradise and we want to share with you some of absolute best places to see.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking a Dry Lake Bed: Southern CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/25/boondocking-a-dry-lake-bed-southern-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking a Dry Lake Bed: Southern CA" /><published>2019-03-25T16:16:25+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-25T16:16:25+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/25/boondocking-a-dry-lake-bed-southern-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/25/boondocking-a-dry-lake-bed-southern-ca/">&lt;p&gt;There’s just something so striking about the patterns that form in dry cracked earth – it’s pretty dang photogenic. That’s exactly what you’ll find here at Silurian Dry Lake Bed, just north of Baker, California. Be aware though, you will also find incredibly strong winds – so much so that we kept both our slides in the entire time and had to park in a way that shielded our RV door because otherwise the wind was ripping it out of our hands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Dry2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dog on dry lake bed with RV&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Peppy soaking up the sun and the scents on the breeze&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on BLM land with a max stay of 14 days and no on-site amenities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 35.5266, -116.1785&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no specific entry road, just look for paths that others have used so you can minimize your impact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were here Feb. 27-29, 2019 and had moderate temperatures but super strong winds – I would guess up to 50mph&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be aware of any precipitation in the forecast, I imagine it’s a muddy mess when it rains and you could easily get stuck&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We had no problem working and streaming video on AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see more photos and reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/silurian-dry-lake-bed&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Dry3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dog on dry lake bed with man&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Paco especially loves to run in the great wide open&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a very brief stay for us, just a couple of nights on our way to Death Valley but from the photos we saw it looked like such an intriguing place, we had to go check it out. There was no one else out there on our first night and the next day we saw someone else had arrived but they respectfully put so much distance between us I’m not even sure what type of rig it was! This wide open area is simply perfect for dog owners. We love when we can let our pups run wild and free and there seems to be something about the wind that really energizes them. The large cracks in the ground sometimes caused the occasional falter but for the most part it was a perfect running ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Dry4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dog scratching her ear on a dry lake bed&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Sometimes you just gotta stop everything and scratch that itch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed getting out on our bikes and touring around the dry lake bed, we actually did this a couple different times it was so much fun. It’s pretty dang freeing to be able to cover a lot of ground, in any direction, with no worries about obstructions or traffic. You could just ride and ride. Pro tip: bike into the wind on your way out so that you can have it at your back for the ride home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Dry5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man biking on dry lake bed&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Feeling carefree and riding into the sunset&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a little difficult to fall asleep with sound of the howling wind and the rocking of the RV but once asleep it didn’t wake us up. We ended up rearranging for the second night so that the nose of RV was pointed into the wind and it wasn’t hitting the bedroom directly – and as mentioned above, we also angled so that the RV door was more protected and that made a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brad had read about some wild hot springs in the nearby town of Tecopa, so we planned to stop as we were headed to our next destination. Unfortunately, these were not the idyllic, instagram-worthy type of hot springs…these were mucky-bottomed, smelly, slimy and tepid springs…we got in to try them out but I don’t think I was in there more than 2 minutes! Our feet easily sunk over a foot deep into the muck and it was just pretty icky. There are developed hot springs in the town which I’m sure are much much nicer, so if you’d like to soak, we would recommend shelling out a little cash…sometimes you really do get what you pay for!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out all the fun in our video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/Qk-G3VMaImA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Free Camping&quot;, &quot;California&quot;]" /><summary type="html">There’s just something so striking about the patterns that form in dry cracked earth – it’s pretty dang photogenic. That’s exactly what you’ll find here at Silurian Dry Lake Bed, just north of Baker, California. Be aware though, you will also find incredibly strong winds – so much so that we kept both our slides in the entire time and had to park in a way that shielded our RV door because otherwise the wind was ripping it out of our hands!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">San Diego, CA: Aquarium, Whales &amp;amp; Hiking Iron Mountain</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/21/san-diego-ca-aquarium-whales-hiking-iron-mountain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="San Diego, CA: Aquarium, Whales &amp; Hiking Iron Mountain" /><published>2019-03-21T16:16:25+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-21T16:16:25+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/21/san-diego-ca-aquarium-whales-hiking-iron-mountain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/21/san-diego-ca-aquarium-whales-hiking-iron-mountain/">&lt;p&gt;After spending a couple weeks in the Anza Borrego Desert State Park we were excited to get back over to the coast – this time to meet-up with my sister and our parents! We booked a stay at Lilac Oaks RV Park in Valley Center and had about a twenty minute drive each day to where they were all staying in Escondido. We hosted my parents for a couple nights in the RV which is always fun but sadly we had nothing but cold and rain and so we spent most of the time just hanging out and working on small projects in the rig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV in a shaded RV park&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;This site was pretty unlevel and our steps ended up being really high off the ground&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We weren’t totally in love with this RV park – it treated us well but there were some hiccups that are worth mentioning. For anyone in a big rig, you’ll want to be aware that the roads throughout the park are narrow, single lanes with large speed bumps and large cracks in the concrete. It just made for a very slow, bumpy, rocky journey anytime we came and went. Additionally, the highway to get here is pretty dang windy but definitely worse if you come straight over from I-15. It’s best to approach from the south/southwest if possible! There are definitely a lot of full-time residents at the park and there’s just a bit of a run-down, rustic look to things. I will say that everyone we met was very nice and helpful, and we always felt perfectly safe and welcome. The definite positive sides of this park were that the washers and dryers were just $1/each per load and the showers were nice and hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iron-mountain&quot;&gt;IRON MOUNTAIN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as activities and excursions we packed as much as we could into our weekend days when everyone was free. One of the more daring things we did was to hike Iron Mountain for sunset! It’s a 5.5 mile hike from the parking lot at Poway Road and Highway 67 but there are several different starting points to make for a longer hike if you want. We brought our Dad with us and since he hasn’t done a lot of hiking we opted for the shortest route – plus we would be coming down in the dark and didn’t need to prolong that any more than necessary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People standing under the Iron Mtn sign&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;All smiles before the big hike!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man silhouetted against a colorful sunset&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It sure was pretty to be up there for sunset&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the recent rain we saw tons of little streams in and around the trail nearly the entire way to the top and there were some pretty muddy/wet clay sections to avoid. We did this hike in late February in very cool weather and were thankful we brought hats and gloves (and lights!) for the way back down. It’s definitely a rugged, rocky trail and you need to be very aware of your footing so you don’t twist an ankle but we all had a great time and enjoyed our picnic at the top for sunset. The way back down in the dark was a little hairy and having lights is a must but it was definitely an unforgettable hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;birch-aquarium&quot;&gt;BIRCH AQUARIUM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are huge lovers of ocean life and really enjoy aquariums so for one of our days we packed everyone up and headed down to La Jolla to check out the Birch Aquarium. It’s a fairly small and popular aquarium but the admission rates are reasonable compared to others we’ve visited and we really love seahorses, which this aquarium had several different varieties of! They also have jellyfish, small sharks, eels, coral reefs, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of a seahorse in an aquarium&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It was so mesmerizing watching them glide from plant to plant&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After meandering the various tanks in the dim light, it was a crazy bright contrast to step out into the sunshine on their huge patio. Out there you’ll find some artifcial pools with small sea creatures and a touch pool. You also get a gorgeous sweeping view of the La Jolla shoreline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful blue ocean view in La Jolla&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We actually went sea cave kayaking here after our wedding many years ago!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whale-watching&quot;&gt;WHALE WATCHING&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last big adventure during this visit was to head out on a whale watching tour! We were in season to be able to see whales migrating both north and south so we were hopeful to be able to see at least one. We were onboard a two level boat that had about 100 passengers and our guide was a marine biologist who shared interesting facts nearly the entire time. Definitely plan to bring your own snacks and drinks though because things can be a bit spendy – coolers weren’t allowed but backpacks were. We found a Groupon deal for the tour which ended up being something like $125 total for our group of six.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Group of people on a whale watching boat&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our family had such a great time together and whale watching was definitely a highlight&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much anticipation and seeing a distant spout on the horizon we eventually caught up to a magnificant gray whale who showed itself to us twice! Both times we got a tail wave which was just incredible and we loved seeing the ‘rainblow’ which is when the mist from the blowhole spout creates a rainbow :) We also had dozens of dolphins following alongside the tour boat, jumping and playing in the wake – a mix of adults and babies! It was definitely a rich experience and one I hope to have again. We later learned that a couple weeks after our tour (which was on February 24, 2019) there was a ‘humpback whale invasion’ and feeding frenzy in the area where we had been!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/SD_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whale flukes in Mission Bay, San Diego&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;I actually got pretty choked up seeing this -- it was magical&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to watch the video for all the fun and especially our whale footage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/R9DB3QVDl_w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="California" /><summary type="html">After spending a couple weeks in the Anza Borrego Desert State Park we were excited to get back over to the coast – this time to meet-up with my sister and our parents! We booked a stay at Lilac Oaks RV Park in Valley Center and had about a twenty minute drive each day to where they were all staying in Escondido. We hosted my parents for a couple nights in the RV which is always fun but sadly we had nothing but cold and rain and so we spent most of the time just hanging out and working on small projects in the rig.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Incredible Oregon:Fantastic Stops &amp;amp; Activities</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/20/incredible-oregon-favorite-stops-activities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incredible Oregon:&lt;br&gt;Fantastic Stops &amp; Activities" /><published>2019-03-20T11:36:51+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T11:36:51+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/20/incredible-oregon-favorite-stops-activities</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/20/incredible-oregon-favorite-stops-activities/">&lt;p&gt;As you might know, Brad and I live and travel full-time in our motorhome, visiting and photographing as many beautiful places as we can. Oregon is one of those states that is bursting with beauty and we find ourselves passing through every year. Even though we’ve explored a lot within the state, we’re always adding new places to the travel list and are always trying to see new waterfalls – there’s over two hundred! Be aware that the rainy season can be from October through May, but with the right attitude (and outdoor gear) the misty fog, rain showers, and sun bursts just add to the dramatic beauty  of the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’ve compiled isn’t meant to be an exhaustive list of Oregon tourist destinations (I don’t even have Portland on the list – that deserves it’s own post!) rather it’s a collection of some of our favorite stops and things to do. You can find videos about most of these places on our Oregon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL8m4FF4S9RxY-9gshqPVIRE6S41Zx9Vgb&quot;&gt;playlist&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado: some of our absolute favorite things to see and do in the gorgeous green state of Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/OregonSites.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Numbered point on a map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-crater-lake-national-park&quot;&gt;1. CRATER LAKE NATIONAL PARK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Klamath County&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 42.920289, -122.162369&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue sky and incredible blue water at Crater Lake&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The unbelievably blue water of Crater Lake&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are a number of National Monuments and National Historic Sites in the state of Oregon, Crater Lake is its only National Park. People from all over the world visit this fairly remote alpine lake to gaze at its incredible deep blue and crystal clear waters. Crater Lake is the deepest lake in the US and it’s also considered one of the snowiest inhabited places in the US as well – snow is typically on the ground from October through June and often into July, meaning that the rim drive around the lake has a very short window of being fully open. Swimming is allowed in the lake, but only at one place, accessed from the Cheetwood Cove Trail. There are several unique rock formations and spires in the park worth checking out and the star-gazing can be downright incredible. Wildfires have become more common in the area in the Fall, with hazy skies obscuring views of the lake. Camping is available in the park or hotel rooms are available at Crater Lake Lodge – although you might have to book this up to two years in advance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We tent camped in a campground within the park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-samuel-h-boardman-scenic-corridor&quot;&gt;2. SAMUEL H. BOARDMAN SCENIC CORRIDOR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brookings, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 42.191800, -124.367000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dramatic beach with many off-shore sea stacks&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Secret Beach at low tide&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The southern Oregon coast is arguably the most beautiful section of coastline in the entire state – full of off-shore sea stacks, arches and natural bridges. The Samuel H. Boardman Scenic Corridor stretches 12 miles along Highway 101, with several small pull-outs and short trails leading to jaw-dropping beauty. Arch Rock, Natural Bridges, Secret Beach, and Seal Cove (GPS above) are all fantastic stops and easily searchable on Google maps. Secret Beach is only accessible at low tide, so be sure to check tide tables as you plan your visit. It does require some agility to scramble down the rocks to Secret Beach and always be aware of dangerous sneaker waves – a common occurance on the Oregon coast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Harris Beach State Park in Brookings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-face-rock-state-scenic-viewpoint&quot;&gt;3. FACE ROCK STATE SCENIC VIEWPOINT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bandon, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 43.105089, -124.433922&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ocean scene with large rocks offshore&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Being here at low tide was absolutely incredible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing Face Rock had been on my list for many years but I didn’t realize what an incredible spot it actually is. I had thought that the only draw was the large off-shore rock resembling a face, but there are in fact dozens of rocky spires out in the water and close to shore that make this one enchanting place. What made our experience unforgettable was visiting here during a negative tide (an extreme low tide) and serendipitously at a time when artist Denny Dyke had created one of his incredible sand drawings. He does them four times a month and you can check out his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sandypathbandon.com/public-schedule&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to see the schedule.
While the view from the parking lot is great (seen above) we would definitely recommend taking the stairway down to the beach. At low tide you’ll find sea caves and tide pools, and you’ll be able to get really close to some of the towering rock formations. Be aware, the parking area is a small loop and can only accomodate about 15 cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Bullards Beach State Park in Bandon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-seal-rock-state-recreation-site&quot;&gt;4. SEAL ROCK STATE RECREATION SITE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seal Rock, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.497365, -124.082790&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset on the Oregon coast with rocky spires&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We caught this beautiful sunset on my birthday a few years ago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You really can’t go wrong visiting anywhere on the Oregon coast so if you find yourself along the central portion we highly recommend visiting Seal Rock State Recreation Site – and all the better if you can visit at low tide and/or sunset. Not only is there the massive Elephant Rock (not pictured), jagged spires rise out of the water not far off shore and with binoculars or a zoom lens you might just spy some seals hanging out on the distant rocks. Tide pools reveal anenomes, starfish and other wonders. Nearby is the charming town of Yachats, a perfect place to incorporate into this visit. Check out the local fare at Yachats Brewing or get oyster shooters and seafood lasanga at nearby Drift Inn. The Green Salmon is a popular little bakery and a great spot to grab breakfast or coffee. The coastline along this small town is especially rocky and picturesque, and several available beach rental homes make this an excellent place to spend a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; McKinley’s Marina &amp;amp; RV Park in Waldport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-float-the-willamette-river&quot;&gt;5. FLOAT THE WILLAMETTE RIVER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eugene, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.045233, -123.026374&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;woman on a kayak with people on a beach&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Spending time at the river is a great way to beat the summer heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better summertime activity is there than being on the water on a hot day. While much of the river between Springfield and Eugene is a calm easy float, there are definitely sections that require your attention and one in particular that requires some swift maneuvering. We always launch from the boat ramp at Island Park (GPS listed above), then, after a little more than a river mile you’ll encounter a section that requires you to make a hard right to go around a fairly swift curve. There will be a sign saying to stay to the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of Willamette River with guiding arrows&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;You'll need to follow the path of the white arrows, just before passing under Interstate 5 (a large concrete bridge)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a real possibility that your watercraft could flip so always wear a life jacket, carry a whistle, and let someone know your plans that day. That being said, floating the Willamette is one of our favorite summertime activities and is mostly quite relaxing. There are a couple different sections of small rapids that add a little excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eugene is also home to many fantastic restaurants, breweries, coffee shops and bakeries so be sure to include some dining in your day out. For food we would recommend Cornucopia, The Bier Stein, Sushi Pure, Cafe Yumm, Pizza Research Institute, Metropol Bakery, and Tacovore. For breweries we love Oakshire, Coldfire, Hop Valley and Ninkasi. For great views of downtown, take a drive up Skinner Butte or for a good workout consider hiking up Spencer Butte or Mount Pisgah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Not helpful…we’ve just stayed with friends when visiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-visit-sahalie--koosah-falls&quot;&gt;6. VISIT SAHALIE &amp;amp; KOOSAH FALLS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sisters, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.348302, -121.995797&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking at a raging waterfall from the top&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Be sure to check out the trail that takes you to the top of Sahalie Falls -- definitely worth it for a closer look&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An incredible amount of beauty lies between Eugene and Bend along Highway 126 so pack a picnic and take a day to explore it! Sahalie Falls is an impressive 100’ tall waterfall flowing over a moss-covered natural lava dam. The viewpoint for Sahalie is just a short walk from the parking area (GPS above). On sunny days this powerful waterfall casts a rainbow in it’s mist, adding to the magic. There’s a side trail to the right that will take you to the top of Sahalie Falls. Be sure to also take the time to hike downstream along the clear turqouise waters of the McKenzie River to reach Koosah Falls, another impressive waterfall dropping 70’ into a wide pool – about 30 minutes on a pine covered trail, with some steps, through the lush forest. You can make it a 2.6 mile loop by continuing to Carmen Reservoir crossing to the other side of the river, and walking back upstream to Sahalie. If parking at Sahalie is full, there’s also a lot at Koosah Falls. While you’re in the area, you might consider the hike to Tamolich Pool (aka Blue Pool), taking a soak at Belknap Hot Springs Lodge, or paddling on nearby Clear Lake with it’s incredible clarity – you can see preserved trees on the lake bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve only visited here en route to Bend or as a day trip from Eugene –not as an overnight stop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-explore-the-city-of-bend&quot;&gt;7. EXPLORE THE CITY OF BEND&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bend, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.031876, -121.566307&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large and fast moving waterfall&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It's a relatively short and easy walk from the parking lot to get this view of Tumalo Falls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the outdoor enthusiast or craft beer lover, Bend is a place not to miss. This hip mountain town on the Deschutes River has more breweries per capita than any other city in Oregon. Download the Bend Ale Trail app to check-in at the breweries you visit – some offer check-in perks like Buy 1, Get 1 deals. While you can’t really go wrong in choosing a brewery, we especially enjoy the food and beer flights at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craftoregon.com/&quot;&gt;Craft Kitchen &amp;amp; Brewery&lt;/a&gt;.  Visit Mt. Bachelor for winter or spring skiing or in the summer for hiking and mountain biking.  The Les Schwab Ampitheater draws quality music acts every summer so be sure to check out their events calendar. If you love to be on the water,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oldmilldistrict.com/stay-play-bend/how-to-float-deschutes-river/&quot;&gt;floating&lt;/a&gt; the Deschutes River is fantastic way to spend an afternoon – there are even outfitters to help you with gear rental and shuttling. Tumalo Falls (GPS above) is an easy but popular hike about 10 miles west of town. There’s a $5 parking fee or it’s free with your National Parks pass. With it’s fairly small parking lot, visiting on a weekday is recommended. Get great photos just a short walk from the lot then head to the top of Tumalo Falls for dramatic views. You can continue hiking upriver another mile to reach Double Falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We boondocked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/forest-road-260&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in the National Forest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-hike-at-smith-rock-state-park&quot;&gt;8. HIKE AT SMITH ROCK STATE PARK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terrebonne, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 44.363860, -121.140409&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rocky cliff walls and spires with a river&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;It can get really hot in the summer months so make sure to hike with plenty of water&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unique stop in central Oregon is just 45 minutes north of the city of Bend, but feels like a little slice of Zion National Park. We loved the challenging 5-mile Misery Ridge loop. You can see the switchbacks of this trail in the above photo. If you prefer a more mellow visit strolling along the river still offers beautiful views, although it is a fairly steep trail down to the river. Smith Rock State Park is also a super popular rock climbing destination with more than 1,000 bolted climbing routes. The park itself can get incredibly busy, so we would suggest trying to visit on a weekday. With parking for about 400 cars, the park easily sees 3x that many visitors on warm weather weekends. There are 6 RV parking spaces located at the GPS coordinates above but no RV camping anywhere at the park. There’s a day use fee of $5 with self-pay stations near the parking areas. To see more about the park amenities, tent camping, and hiking trails check out the state park &lt;a href=&quot;https://oregonstateparks.org/index.cfm?do=parkPage.dsp_parkPage&amp;amp;parkId=36&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve stayed overnight at the Walmart in Redmond (1 night only) and we’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/forest-road-260&quot;&gt;boondocked&lt;/a&gt; outside Bend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-paddle-trillium-lake-at-mt-hood&quot;&gt;9. PADDLE TRILLIUM LAKE AT MT. HOOD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mt. Hood National Forest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 45.266408, -121.741273&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sandy lakeshore beach with snow-capped peak in the distance&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Now how inviting is this scene!?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mt. Hood is one of Oregon’s most recognizable peaks and it’s highest. Just about an hour and a half drive from the Portland airport and Hood is known for having almost yearround skiing. Timberline Lodge offers offers daily skiing until September and October, then it switches to weekends, as conditions allow. There are many beautiful alpine lakes in the area but we love the accessiblity and view from Trillium Lake. Bring a picnic and blanket and enjoy the views from shore or if you want a more unique experience, rent a canoe, kayak or paddleboard from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mthoodoutfitters.com/&quot;&gt;Mt. Hood Outfitters&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a $5 day use fee at this lake. We like to park in the lot closest to the beach pictured (GPS above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Trillium Lake Campground&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-hike-the-multnomah-wahkeena-waterfall-trail&quot;&gt;10. HIKE THE MULTNOMAH-WAHKEENA WATERFALL TRAIL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Columbia River Gorge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 45.575253, -122.128178&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two impressive waterfalls&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Multnomah Falls on the left and the difficult-to-access base of Ecola Falls on the right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hike is a fantastic way to experience the majesty of the Columbia River Gorge, just 25 miles east of the Portland airport. Multnomah Falls is definitely one of the most iconic waterfalls in the state and worth seeing just on it’s own but if you’re looking to experience even more of Oregon’s gorgeous waterfalls, there are nearly 50 along this scenic highway corridor! Regarding the Multnomah-Wahkeena hike: not only do you experience Multnomah Falls from the top and bottom, you’ll see five other beautiful falls, and several unnamed falls. This is a moderate 5-mile roundtrip loop. You can hike the loop in either direction but we started at the Wahkeena Falls trailhead (GPS listed above) and ended at Multnomah. There is significant elevation gain along the hike but also flatter portions. This area can be extremely busy and parking can be difficult, so arriving early in the day is definitely recommended. There are lots of other waterfalls nearby and most of them are labeled on Google maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; We boodocked in Cascade Locks but unfortunately it’s no longer allowed at that spot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-explore-the-city-of-astoria&quot;&gt;11. EXPLORE THE CITY OF ASTORIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Astoria, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 46.181140, -123.817029&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge and marina on a sunny day&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Astoria-Megler Bridge as seen from the marina&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many quaint little communities along the Oregon Coast but possibly none so famous as Astoria. It’s the oldest city west of the Rockies, it’s where Lewis and Clark ended their westward expedition (well, technically at Fort Clatsop just 5 miles southwest of Astoria), and it’s been the backdrop of several movies including The Goonies, Short Circuit, Into the Wild, and The Ring. Astoria sits in the very northwest corner of Oregon where the Columbia River meets the Pacific Ocean. Not only are there fantastic breweries– Buoy and Fort George are favorites – there’s also the riverwalk (fun to explore by foot, bicycle or trolley) and climbing up the Astoria Column to get great views of the area (GPS above). We would recommend visiting the wonderful Sunday Farmer’s Market or heading to Fort Stevens State Park to see the ghostly remains of the Peter Iredale shipwreck, which ran aground in 1906.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Golf Course &amp;amp; RV Park in Astoria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-explore-the-wallowa-mountains&quot;&gt;12. EXPLORE THE WALLOWA MOUNTAINS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joseph, Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 45.280887, -117.211842&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/2018Best4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crystal clear lake surrounding by mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Clockwise from top left: Wallowa Lake, Views from Mt. Howard, and views along the Hurricane Creek Trail&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wallowa Mountains are an unexpected and awe-inspiring gem located in the far northeast corner of the state. They’re known as the Swiss Alps of Oregon and it’s no surprise that this area also makes it on the Seven Wonders of Oregon list. It’s definitely an out of the way place to visit, but oh so worth it. This area sees a lot of winter snow, so the best time to catch open trails is during the summer months. RV sites are available at Wallowa Lake State Park (GPS above) and at a handful of nearby RV parks – be aware that reservations can fill quickly. In addition to boating and kayaking on the gorgeous lake be sure to hit some of the hiking trails. We loved the Hurricane Creek trail in the Eagle Cap Wilderness. For especially dramatic views take the tram up Mt. Howard and hike the 2 mile loop at the top. Tram tickets are a bit spendy at $35/person but the ride is adventurous, the views are phenomenal and at the top there’s a cafe with outdoor seating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we camped:&lt;/strong&gt; Wallowa Lake State Park and nearby Scenic Meadows RV Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, your turn! We’d love to hear about your favorite stops in the state. Leave us a comment below with your must-see places in this Pacific Wonderland.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Oregon&quot;]" /><summary type="html">As you might know, Brad and I live and travel full-time in our motorhome, visiting and photographing as many beautiful places as we can. Oregon is one of those states that is bursting with beauty and we find ourselves passing through every year. Even though we’ve explored a lot within the state, we’re always adding new places to the travel list and are always trying to see new waterfalls – there’s over two hundred! Be aware that the rainy season can be from October through May, but with the right attitude (and outdoor gear) the misty fog, rain showers, and sun bursts just add to the dramatic beauty of the landscape.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking Rockhouse Road: Borrego Springs, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/06/boondocking-rockhouse-road-borrego-springs-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking Rockhouse Road: Borrego 
Springs, CA" /><published>2019-03-06T17:37:39+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-06T17:37:39+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/06/boondocking-rockhouse-road-borrego-springs-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/03/06/boondocking-rockhouse-road-borrego-springs-ca/">&lt;p&gt;It was probably in December when my sister shared with me that a super bloom was expected in the California deserts this spring. I didn’t really know if our schedule would line up but it certainly stayed in the back of my mind. The heart of the super bloom was predicted for late February/early March and unfortunately we ended up having plans and reservations elsewhere during that time frame. We were however able to visit the Anza Borrego desert in early February to witness what was called the first pulse of the super bloom. The base camp for our stay near Borrego Springs was a popular free camping area called Rockhouse Trail Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on BLM land with a max stay of 14 days and no on-site amenities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 33.2978, -116.2867&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The town of Borrego Springs is about 8 miles away with pretty much all you might need: post office, grocery store, liquor store, laundromat, farmer’s market and shopping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were here Feb. 10-17, 2019 and had daytime temps in the low 60s, overnight lows in the 40s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The camping area is mostly dirt and gravel and can easily accommodate 50+ rigs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cell service varies greatly throughout the area and we had the best speeds closest to the highway on AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see more photos and reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/rockhouse&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Anza3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RVs in a dirt lot with mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our view out the living room window&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This boondocking site is generally not our preferred way to camp: an open dirt lot surrounded by several other campers, no real privacy and little to prevent someone from parking right next to you – which did happen here…but what can you do, it’s public land and everyone has a right to be here. Best to just enjoy your beautiful surroundings and make a new friend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually many things we enjoy about this location, the first one being that it’s free and not too far from San Diego. It makes for a nice stop when we’re heading to or from the coast or just looking for a place to ride out some of the winter. The small town of Borrego Springs is quite charming. I’ve really enjoyed their thrift store, the grocery store is well stocked (but lacking in organic produce), and amazingly I found my all-time favorite gluten-free beer at their small liquor store: Uinta Free Form IPA. I haven’t been able to find it anywhere else, not even in Utah! There’s also a farmer’s market on Friday mornings, November - April, which I sadly did not make it to but perhaps they have some organic produce there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of interesting hikes and off-road trails in the area that we hoped to check out: Sheep Canyon Hike, Calcite Mine, Wind Caves, Font’s Point and the Pictograph Trail to Smuggler’s Canyon but we didn’t get a chance to explore any of these because we were having engine trouble in our Xterra! They are definitely still on the list for next time. We really enjoyed the short and easy hike right from our campsite to some fun rock artwork – had we known about it sooner that might have been a daily hike!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Anza2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;People near rock art with mountain backdrop&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Such a gorgeous backdrop -- we love the low mountains surrounding this area&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also loved checking out the giant metal sculptures at Galleta Meadows. These had been on my travel list for nearly two years – basically since I learned about them right after we visited here the last time! The dragon is definitely the most impressive but they are all really interesting and there’s so much detail in each one. You can find the dragon at GPS: 33.290036, -116.376537 but keep your eyes peeled as you drive around, there are sculptures scattered all over town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Anza5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large metal dragon sculpture&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Galleta Meadows sculptures are by local artist Ricardo Breceda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, we were here at the very start of the superbloom and got to see a wide variety of sweet little desert wildflowers. I found this really great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abdnha.org/pages/03flora/reports/current.htm&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; that gives current information on where to find the best clusters of flowers – definitely bookmark that one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Anza6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Petite wildflowers in the desert&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Not sure what this one is but it was one of the largest type of flowers we saw&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Anza4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Woman looking at a field of small wildflowers&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Parts of the desert were just starting to get color when we visited&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you need water or to use an RV dump station, you can use the services at the Anza Borrego State Park Campground for $10. We actually filled our fresh water before coming up here from the Carrizo Badlands area. Brad had found Agua Caliente County Park, where we used the dump and got water for $7 and then took advantage of their hot springs for just $3 each! Pro-tip: the indoor hot pool is adults only from 9:30a-10:30a!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/PjWJ6QOwQGs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">It was probably in December when my sister shared with me that a super bloom was expected in the California deserts this spring. I didn’t really know if our schedule would line up but it certainly stayed in the back of my mind. The heart of the super bloom was predicted for late February/early March and unfortunately we ended up having plans and reservations elsewhere during that time frame. We were however able to visit the Anza Borrego desert in early February to witness what was called the first pulse of the super bloom. The base camp for our stay near Borrego Springs was a popular free camping area called Rockhouse Trail Road.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking Carrizo Badlands: Anza Borrego, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/27/boondocking-carrizo-badlands-anza-borrego-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking Carrizo Badlands: Anza Borrego, CA" /><published>2019-02-27T17:37:39+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-27T17:37:39+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/27/boondocking-carrizo-badlands-anza-borrego-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/27/boondocking-carrizo-badlands-anza-borrego-ca/">&lt;p&gt;The Anza Borrego Desert State Park in southeastern California is a dramatic desert terrain full of hiking, camping, badlands, slot canyons, and off-roading trails. Star-gazing is top notch and if it’s been a wet winter you just might catch the desert in bloom in the early springtime. One of our favorite free campsites is the Carrizo Badlands Overlook at the very southern end of the state park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping within the state park&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS: 32.8287, -116.1673&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The closest grocery stores would be in El Centro or Borrego Springs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were here Feb. 6-9, 2019 and had pretty comfortable weather with highs in the 60s, lows in the mid30s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are only a few sites available at the Overlook but much boondocking is available throughout the state park&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The access road is a little rugged, so we prefer to enter and exit at the western end of the Overlook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see more photos and reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/carrizo-badlands-overlook&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Carrizo3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pastel sunset over golden badlands&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;View of the badlands from the overlook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time we stayed here we had several days of strong wind, lots of rain, and more than a couple rainbows. We didn’t have our 4x4 vehicle at that time but we noticed a Jeeping group head down into Canyon Sin Nombre, which is what the Overlook faces. On this visit we were excited to take our Xterra Off Road off-roading. The 4x4 trail is rated as easy but the first mile has a handful of tricky sections. The rest of the 6 mile loop is pretty easy going but with some areas of deep soft sand to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Carrizo6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Car on an off-road trail&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our Xterra, Frida, looking tiny against the canyon walls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a short stay for us here, only three nights, so time flew by quickly. We walked the dogs around the Overlook, we enjoyed sunsets and starry nights, and we got out for a beautiful hike just a few miles down the road at Mountain Palm Springs. We had seen a huge cluster of palm trees from the highway and found out there was a hike to see them. You can do it as a short or long loop, or an out and back. We were short on daylight and just did the out and back option. We only saw one other couple on the hike and had the main oasis all to ourselves. It was an easy hike on rugged terrain and we would highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Carrizo7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man standing in front of a large grove of palm trees&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A beautiful large grove of palm trees awaits you on the trail&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was just a bit north near Borrego Springs and so we wanted to empty our tanks and get some water near Carrizo Badlands. Brad learned of Agua Caliente County Park and not only was it just $7 to use their dump station and get fresh water, they have hot springs pools. It’s $3 per person for a day use pass and at the indoor hot pool they have an adult-only hour from 9:30am-10:30am. We used to really enjoy taking hot soaks in our bathtub back in our stationary days, so we always enjoy a good hot tub or hot springs whenever we get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was then a short 45 mile drive up to Borrego Springs where we got all settled in at a new boondocking spot for the week – but more on that next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out the video below all about our explorations near the Carrizo Badlands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/OhcYyyKNo7c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The Anza Borrego Desert State Park in southeastern California is a dramatic desert terrain full of hiking, camping, badlands, slot canyons, and off-roading trails. Star-gazing is top notch and if it’s been a wet winter you just might catch the desert in bloom in the early springtime. One of our favorite free campsites is the Carrizo Badlands Overlook at the very southern end of the state park.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our Wonderful Wild Week in Carlsbad, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/20/our-wonderful-wild-week-in-carlsbad-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Wonderful Wild Week in Carlsbad, CA" /><published>2019-02-20T15:45:47+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T15:45:47+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/20/our-wonderful-wild-week-in-carlsbad-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/20/our-wonderful-wild-week-in-carlsbad-ca/">&lt;p&gt;We had such a glorious stay last week in Cardiff by the Sea but with a maximum 7 day stay allowed at San Elijo State Beach it was time to change campgrounds. Luckily we only had to move just a few miles up the coast for a stay at the lovely South Carlsbad State Beach Campground. So similar to San Elijo yet oh so different – it’s just a completely different vibe. The Carlsbad campground was just more quiet, more relaxed, and they had a lot more available campsites. We’re not quite sure why so many more people gravitate towards San Elijo but we’ve got some guesses: it connects to a dog friendly beach, there are several great surfing spots nearby, and it’s a short walk to some nice shopping and groceries. Up in Carlsbad you aren’t nearly as close to the city and the beaches maybe aren’t quite as inviting, but it is equally as beautiful and since it wasn’t fully booked we had several days with an open view of the ocean, even from our ‘back row’ campsite!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Cbad3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smooth rocks on a beach&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;South Carlsbad State Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our stay here was wild in several respects. While our first day was sunny and warm, the next several days had thunderstorms in the forecast. The day I went exploring, storms were expected around 2pm, so I figured I had some time to get video and shots down by the water. The wind had been blowing pretty strong that day so it wasn’t great to be out, but the water was still quite beautiful and I saw some kite surfers down the beach so I headed closer to get some better shots of them, which I did. As I was climbing the stairs back up the campground (now a good 1/2 mile from where I started) I saw lightning strike far off shore and sure enough it started to sprinkle. I quickened my pace as the skies opened up more and ended up in a full run before I got back to the RV. We had some crazy loud thunder and lightning and as things were winding down I saw the sun punching through the clouds and sure enough we had quite the amazing double rainbow right over the RV.  If that wasn’t enough, we also ended up having a beautiful sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Cbad2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pink clouds sunset with cliff and ocean&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A dramatic sky makes every picture better!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister lives in the area and for our next wild experience she took us for an outing to the San Diego Safari Park – what a treat. It turned out to be a cool and overcast day with rain in the forecast which meant that the crowds stayed away! We had such awesome luck with seeing very active animals and I got some really fantastic videos. I’m an animal lover through and through so it was a delight to see them. Most were in spacious enclosures, which counts for so much, and there’s just something so beautiful and almost overwhelming about massive yet peaceful animals. I could’ve watched the elephants for hours and the giraffes are just so majestic. Be sure to check out the full episode below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Cbad4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lion at a zoo&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;This guy was so amazing and making low groaning sounds&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also checked out a unique new ‘sport’ with my sister, axe throwing – which was definitely wild! We appreciated the instruction and helpful hints from the people working there and before long we had pretty much nailed the technique with everyone getting some bullseye hits. They offer 30-minute and 60-minute time slots but 30 minutes was plenty for the three of us. They set you up with two boards and so we all had plenty of opportunity to throw. After that we checked out Twisted Horn Meadery. We got a few different flights and enjoyed everything we tried. I was quite surprised the meads weren’t all that sweet considering they are made from honey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the campground – dogs aren’t allowed on the beach here but there is basically one super long road that runs the length of the campground so most campers enjoy walking and jogging along there. There’s a Ralph’s grocery store within walking or biking distance and it’s not terribly far to get into Carlsbad or head south to Encinitas. Some of our favorite eateries in Carlsbad are Pizza Port (which can be really busy and noisy…so be aware), Harbor Fish Cafe, and Lotus Thai and we also checked out Barrel Republic which is a tap house where you pour your own beer. The amount you consume is monitored by a wristband that you wear and scan each time you pull a tap. They had a ton of options plus several of the locally made gluten-reduced beers – just ask them what’s gluten-reduced when you visit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, another fantastic week on the coast. And a good life metaphor: you can’t have a rainbow without a little rain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/bIcsXH7C4D4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;]" /><summary type="html">We had such a glorious stay last week in Cardiff by the Sea but with a maximum 7 day stay allowed at San Elijo State Beach it was time to change campgrounds. Luckily we only had to move just a few miles up the coast for a stay at the lovely South Carlsbad State Beach Campground. So similar to San Elijo yet oh so different – it’s just a completely different vibe. The Carlsbad campground was just more quiet, more relaxed, and they had a lot more available campsites. We’re not quite sure why so many more people gravitate towards San Elijo but we’ve got some guesses: it connects to a dog friendly beach, there are several great surfing spots nearby, and it’s a short walk to some nice shopping and groceries. Up in Carlsbad you aren’t nearly as close to the city and the beaches maybe aren’t quite as inviting, but it is equally as beautiful and since it wasn’t fully booked we had several days with an open view of the ocean, even from our ‘back row’ campsite!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">San Elijo State Beach: Cardiff by the Sea, CA</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/13/san-elijo-state-beach-cardiff-by-the-sea-ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="San Elijo State Beach: Cardiff by the Sea, CA" /><published>2019-02-13T22:16:50+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T22:16:50+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/13/san-elijo-state-beach-cardiff-by-the-sea-ca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/13/san-elijo-state-beach-cardiff-by-the-sea-ca/">&lt;p&gt;As much as we love to boondock in the middle of nowhere, we still find ourselves drawn to certain destinations and we’re definitely willing to spend a little cash to be there. Whenever possible, our favorite option is to stay in state park campgrounds – there’s usually plenty of natural beauty, you’ll typically find much better rates than private RV parks, they are often close to bike paths, and when you’re along the California coast it’s just one of the best ways to be able to stay beachfront. We lived in North San Diego County for two years before we hit the road and we still love what the area has to offer: that laid back surf town vibe, beautiful beaches, healthy restaurants, great breweries and so much recreation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two people on a trail overlooking the ocean&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Enjoying a sweet little trail in the Self Realization Fellowship gardens&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;san-elijo-state-beach-campground&quot;&gt;SAN ELIJO STATE BEACH CAMPGROUND&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Elijo is a super popular campground among travelers and locals alike, and especially so for surfers. You can make reservations up to six months in advance and you’ll definitely need to plan ahead for a stay here. Reservations are made through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reservecalifornia.com/CaliforniaWebHome/&quot;&gt;Reserve California&lt;/a&gt; website. There are three sections to this campground and our preferred area is the southern section since it puts us closest to the dog friendly section of the beach. We’ve found the middle section to usually be very busy and crowded with little privacy between sites. Most recently we stayed in the northern section and appreciated that it was a little quieter and seemed to have more vegetation between sites. There are many ocean view sites but we always opt for the less expensive back row. You can usually see at least a bit of ocean even from there, or you might get lucky with an empty site in front you, if only for a day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rv with palm trees at sunset&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The northern section has privacy fencing against the highway, which is definitely an added bonus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maximum vehicle length is 35’ and the maximum stay allowed is 7 days. There’s a fee to use the dump station and there are potable water spigots located there as well for filling your tank. Most of the sites are dry camping but there are some hookup sites available for an extra fee. During the summer there’s a camp store and a few laundry machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re sensitive to noise, this might not be the campground for you. The campground backs right up to Highway 101 and next to that are train tracks. The Coaster and Amtrak trains pass frequently during the day, and due to the nearby pedestrian crossing, they really blast their horns. We actually really appreciate the Coaster train – it’s a fantastic option to get around San Diego County, so we don’t mind hearing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cardiff-by-the-sea&quot;&gt;CARDIFF-BY-THE-SEA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big reasons we enjoy staying at San Elijo is that we love the little community of Cardiff! Everything is so walkable, people are friendly, and there’s fantastic dining. We’ve actually needed to get Paco in to the vet both times we’ve stayed here. The Cardiff Animal Hospital is an easy walk from the campground and we’ve appreciated both of the doctors we’ve worked with. The Seaside Market is a delightful, albeit spendy, grocery store with fantastic selections of organic produce, wine, and local beer, as well as the usual grocery store staples. They also have a great deli and seafood counter. There’s Pipes Cafe across the street for breakfast and I make a point to drop by the Rancho Coastal Thrift Store – I always seem to find something I like and it supports the Rancho Coastal Humane Society, which is where we adopted both Paco and Pepper from! We also really love to stop at VG Donuts or grab a pint at Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encinitas&quot;&gt;ENCINITAS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually lived in Encinitas for two years and so we have a close connection to this surfer community as well. It’s a quick bike ride from San Elijo to downtown Encinitas where there are fantastic restaurants, breweries, bars and shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome to Encinitas sign&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;We love the Welcome sign --  it definitely captures the spirit of this community!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture Brewing recently opened a tap room here and we were delighted to find that most of the beers they offer are gluten-reduced! As an IPA lover who recently had to give up gluten, it’s been amazing to find several breweries that offer this! Some of our favorite budget friendly eateries downtown are Lotus Cafe, GoodOnYa, Swami’s Cafe and the Potato Shack but if you’re looking for fine dining along here there is plenty. Just a bit beyond downtown is the beautiful and popular Moonlight Beach where you can have campfires or play beach volleyball. If you’ve got the time, you might consider taking in a movie at the historic La Paloma theater or strolling the beautiful and free Self Realization Fellowship gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Busy beach scene with palm trees and volleyball&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The popular and quaint Moonlight Beach near downtown&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also catch the Coaster train here and head off on any number of adventures. We especially love to take it to Old Town (a wonderful place to stroll and get lunch) or all the way to Santa Fe Depot in the heart of downtown, from there it’s just a few blocks to the bayfront and all sorts of dining and sightseeing. We would recommend the inexpensive ferry over to Coronado Island to get amazing views of the downtown skyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Elijo6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;City lights reflecting on the water&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A shot from the ferry, getting ready to dock at Broadway Pier&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really enjoy North County, and all of San Diego, and we’ve made several visits here.
Watch our most recent visit below or check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/WHJIq9kIYa8&quot;&gt;San Diego County&lt;/a&gt; playlist on YouTube. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/jp9uxUdn5FU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;California&quot;, &quot;Favorite Campsites&quot;]" /><summary type="html">As much as we love to boondock in the middle of nowhere, we still find ourselves drawn to certain destinations and we’re definitely willing to spend a little cash to be there. Whenever possible, our favorite option is to stay in state park campgrounds – there’s usually plenty of natural beauty, you’ll typically find much better rates than private RV parks, they are often close to bike paths, and when you’re along the California coast it’s just one of the best ways to be able to stay beachfront. We lived in North San Diego County for two years before we hit the road and we still love what the area has to offer: that laid back surf town vibe, beautiful beaches, healthy restaurants, great breweries and so much recreation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding Community on the Road</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/06/finding-community-on-the-road/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding Community on the Road" /><published>2019-02-06T09:20:49+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T09:20:49+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/06/finding-community-on-the-road</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/02/06/finding-community-on-the-road/">&lt;p&gt;Community. It’s something that nearly every person craves and you might think that moving into an RV and hitting the road sounds like a lonely endeavor – well, like many things in life, it will be what you make it to be. There are so many options for meeting other travelers: you might meet people at your campground or your neighbors out in the boondocks or you can go straight to the source and join an RVing group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Several people smiling at camera&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Friendships seem to develop quickly among travelers -- there's so much common ground&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-so-many-options&quot;&gt;THERE ARE SO MANY OPTIONS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some meetups are free but most groups do have a membership fee or you have to buy event tickets, or both. There’s Bob Wells’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cheaprvliving.com/rtr/&quot;&gt;Rubber Tramp Rendevous&lt;/a&gt;: the RTR and the WRTR (which is women-only), these are annual meetups in Quartzsite, AZ. You’ve got the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fmca.com/fmca-events&quot;&gt;FMCA&lt;/a&gt;, the Family Motor Coach Association and the many events they host each year. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rvnomadsthemovie.com/nomadfest/&quot;&gt;Nomadfest&lt;/a&gt; put on by RV Nomads. You might like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rvillagerally.com/&quot;&gt;RVillage Rally&lt;/a&gt; a socializing event with seminars and live music or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://therventrepreneur.com/&quot;&gt;RV Entrepreneur Summit&lt;/a&gt; for networking and strategizing your mobile business. Then there’s the Xscapers – the group we recently joined. The Xscapers are specifically geared towards working age RVers and they host several convergences throughout the year including a trip to Baja, a sky-diving meetup, a summer concert gathering in Colorado and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best part is that you don’t have to chose just one group. We know several folks who attend many of these. Being that we really like to chart our own course, joining just one group made sense for us – we prefer not to have too many scheduled events limiting our travel radius!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Woman hiking in a slot canyon&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There is not one right way to travel or socialize, just get out there and start exploring!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-xscapers-backstory&quot;&gt;OUR XSCAPERS BACKSTORY&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first experience with Xscapers happened totally by accident. It was July 2017 and we were heading to a beautiful boondocking spot in Ketchum, Idaho. I had seen that someone we follow on Instagram was already there. We reached out through the app and made plans to meet. Well, this person knew several other folks in the area as well, and we ended up meeting up with everyone a couple times and learned that most of them were in the Xscapers group. Everyone was really nice and laid back and that kind of laid the foundation for us. The Annual Bash is held every January and since we knew we would be in Florida for January 2018 we didn’t join the group just yet. When we realized we’d be in the desert for January 2019 we figured it was time to see what this group was all about – plus we looked forward to seeing many of those Idaho friends again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RV parked in a sweeping green valley&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The sweet spot we stayed at in Ketchum, Idaho&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attending-our-first-bash&quot;&gt;ATTENDING OUR FIRST BASH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually started off this year at the Xscapers New Years Eve party in Quartzsite which was a fantastic way to ring in 2019 and then 12 days later we attended the Annual Bash in Lake Havasu City, Arizona. The Bash was held at the SARA Park Rodeo Grounds and had 300+ RVs and over 500 people in attendance. They offered several different camping areas so you could choose the one best suited to you: the Solar section, Solo Travelers, Families, the Party section, and the General section. We chose Solar, figuring with the abundant sunshine in the desert we’d be just fine. The organizers did say that if there were cloudy days it would be ok to run a generator in that section if it were only for a couple hours, being thoughtful of your neighbors. We ended up having a couple days with nothing but clouds and rain, but Brad was determined not to rev our noisy genny next to our fully solar capable neighbors, and we made it through!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hundreds of RVs parked at the Rodeo Grounds&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;View of the Rodeo Grounds from our hike up Lizard Peak&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Annual Bash was nine days of speakers and presentations, potlucks and happy hours, games and sports, and music and dancing. There were endless opportunities to meet new people and it was easy to bond over all the shared experiences. Brad really enjoyed playing kickball, hiking some of the awesome nearby trails, and the Xscaper Olympics which had three-legged races, pin the sewer hose on the RV, and limbo among many other activities. Some of my favorite events were the 80s Night dance party, yoga, hiking, and the Margarita Throwdown where dozens of people made their favorite recipe and we all sampled them, mingled, and voted for our favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/AB6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Four new friends in black &amp;amp; white&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Our friends Margot and James just before we all had to say farewell&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just had such a positive experience, made so many friends, had many more late nights than we’re used to, and left with unforgettable memories. We truly did find our community on the road. When the Bash ended, many people broke off into smaller groups to caravan to new places. We had a need to go recharge and unwind at the coast and so off we went. While we’ll still mostly be traveling on our own, we very much look forward to those times ahead when we’ll cross paths with our new tribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our video for all the fun:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/E40FoUZEIGQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="RV Community" /><summary type="html">Community. It’s something that nearly every person craves and you might think that moving into an RV and hitting the road sounds like a lonely endeavor – well, like many things in life, it will be what you make it to be. There are so many options for meeting other travelers: you might meet people at your campground or your neighbors out in the boondocks or you can go straight to the source and join an RVing group.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boondocking at Saddle Mountain BLM: Arizona</title><link href="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/30/boondocking-at-saddle-mountain-blm-arizona/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boondocking at Saddle Mountain BLM: Arizona" /><published>2019-01-30T11:35:13+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T11:35:13+00:00</updated><id>https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/30/boondocking-at-saddle-mountain-blm-arizona</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wanderlandtravelers.com/2019/01/30/boondocking-at-saddle-mountain-blm-arizona/">&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure when I first saw photos of this camping area on social media but I immediately added it to my list of places we should visit. After a short stay in Tempe, we needed to stick around the area but we were ready to get back out boondocking and it was a great time to check out this spot. Brad discovered that this is one of the highest rated boondocking sites in Arizona on our favorite camp-finding app: Campendium, so we were really looking forward to checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-quick-details&quot;&gt;THE QUICK DETAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is free camping on BLM land with a max 14 day stay and no amenities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GPS 33.464, -113.0366&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were here Jan.6-9, 2019 and had daytime highs in the 50s &amp;amp; 60s, lows in the upper 30s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a very rough road at the GPS listed above. We would recommend trying the road 2000’ down the highway – we saw many more rigs over there, leading us to believe that area is more accessible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see more photos and reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campendium.com/saddle-mountain&quot;&gt;Campendium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Saddle2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yellow daisies with blurry RV in the background&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Wildflowers make any campsite 100x better&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, the road listed at the GPS is pretty dang rough and rocky but we went slowly and were able to make it a few sites in from the road. Some more adventurous souls went in further, a class C was several hundred feet beyond us and a skoolie bus was all the way at the base of the mountain. What we didn’t like about the road was that one side is a lot higher than the other, coupled with rocky terrain, rutted spots, and it was narrow. There just wasn’t a need to push our luck by going in further so we didn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Saddle3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two people eating salads in an RV&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Us being content with our decision&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views were fantastic, it was quiet, and there was hiking to be found however there were SO many dang flies around where we were camped. No matter how hard we tried, they inevitably got in and drove us all bonkers! So awful! It became my daily mission to rid the RV of them, but anytime we opened the door more would find their way in. Some reviewers on Campendium have speculated that campers have been dumping their grey tanks out there which attracted the flies – so we would offer this friendly PSA: it’s illegal to dump your grey tank anywhere other than at a dump station, so just don’t do it! It’s not illegal to collect your water in a bucket, as you are using it, and then pour that outside, but once it enters the grey tank it’s definitley a no go and can get very stinky, very quickly. For more on that, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rvtravel.com/more-on-the-gray-area-of-dumping-the-gray-tank/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; interesting article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;has-caption &quot; src=&quot;/images/Saddle4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Highway with out of focus mountains&quot; /&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;There are inspiring views just about everywhere you look&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as things to do around Saddle Mountain, there are some ATV trails, hiking in the mountains, and probably some good mountain biking. Sunset photography and astrophotography are great out here, and we saw a few folks rockhounding, although I don’t know what they were finding. We were here on work days, so aside from dog walks, we just went for a little drive and when that didn’t pan out (we quickly reached an impassable spot much more suited for ATVs) we got the drone in the air – we always love to get that aerial view when we can!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our video for all the fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/jgMcP-UX-1c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Maggie</name></author><category term="[&quot;Arizona&quot;, &quot;Free Camping&quot;]" /><summary type="html">I’m not sure when I first saw photos of this camping area on social media but I immediately added it to my list of places we should visit. After a short stay in Tempe, we needed to stick around the area but we were ready to get back out boondocking and it was a great time to check out this spot. Brad discovered that this is one of the highest rated boondocking sites in Arizona on our favorite camp-finding app: Campendium, so we were really looking forward to checking it out.</summary></entry></feed>